<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A Scripture-catechism for children collected out of the whole body of the Scriptures for the instructing of youth ... presented to fathers of families and masters of schools to train up their children and schollers in the knowledg of God and the Scriptures / by Ambros Rigge.</title>
            <author>Rigge, Ambrose, 1635?-1705.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1672</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 159 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 57 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-12">2011-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A57307</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing R1489</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R26219</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">09390769</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 09390769</idno>
            <idno type="VID">42947</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A57307)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 42947)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1314:16)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A Scripture-catechism for children collected out of the whole body of the Scriptures for the instructing of youth ... presented to fathers of families and masters of schools to train up their children and schollers in the knowledg of God and the Scriptures / by Ambros Rigge.</title>
                  <author>Rigge, Ambrose, 1635?-1705.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>110 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1672.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  Catechisms.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-02</date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-04</date>
            <label>Olivia Bottum</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:42947:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>A Scripture-Catechiſm FOR CHILDREN</p>
            <p>Collected out of the whole Body of the Scriptures, for the inſtructing of Youth with the Word of the Lord in the begin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning, and with his Judgments and Mer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cies ſince the beginning, and with his dealing with his People through out ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Generations, being written for our Learning, in whom the true Light hath ſhined, that they might be taught our Children, and Children's Children, throughout our Generations.</p>
            <p>Preſented to Fathers of Families and Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſters of Schools, to train up their Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren and Schollers in the Knowledg of God and the Scriptures.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>By</hi> Ambros Rigge.</p>
            <q>
               <hi>Come ye Children, and I will teach you the Fear of the Lord,</hi>
               <bibl> Pſal 34. 11.</bibl>
            </q>
            <p>Printed in the Year, 1672.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="catechism">
            <pb facs="tcp:42947:2"/>
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:42947:2"/>
            <head>A Scripture Catechiſm FOR CHILDREN, &amp;c.</head>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Scholler,</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>VVHat is God, who made me and all Creatures?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>Maſter,</speaker>
               <p>A pure and glorious Spirit of Life and Light, <hi>John</hi> 4. 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his Work in the Beginning?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To create Heaven and Earth, and all things therein, <hi>Gen.</hi> 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his firſt day's Work?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To create Light and Darkneſs, and to divide the Light from the Darkneſs, <hi>Gen.</hi> 1. 3, 4, 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his ſecond day's Work?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To place the Firmament in the midſt of the Waters, to divide the Waters from the Waters, verſ. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he call the Firmament?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Heaven; and the gathering toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:42947:3"/>
of the Waters he called the Seas, verſ. 8, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was the Earth formed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Word of God; for he ſaid, Let the dry Land appear, and it was ſo, verſ. 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came the Earth to bring forth Fruit?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Command of God; for he ſaid, Let the Earth bring forth Graſs, and the Herb yielding Seed after his kind, and the Fruit Tree yielding Fruits after his kind, and it was ſo, verſ. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his third day's Work?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To place the Earth and Seas in their proper places, that they might be fruitful, verſ. 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his fourth day's Work?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To place two great Lights in the Firmament, to give light upon the Earth; and to divide the Day from the Night, verſ. 15, 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Which of th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ſe Lights was to rule the Day, and which the Night?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The greater Light was to rule the Day, and the leſſer to rule the Night, verſ. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his fifth day's Work?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To repleniſh the Earth with all li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving Creatures, and Fowls to fly above the
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:42947:3"/>
Earth in the open Firmament of Heaven, verſ. 20, 21.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came they to be Fruitful, and to en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe in the Earth and Seas?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Word of God, who ſaid to the Creatures he had made, Be fruitful and multiply, and fill the Waters in the Seas, and let the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>owl multiply in the Earth, verſ. 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his ſixth day's Work?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To create Man in his own Image, and to give him Dominion over all other Crea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tures which he had made in the Earth and Seas, verſ. 26.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of what was Man created?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of the Duſt of the Ground; and God breathed into his Noſtrils the Breath of Life, ſo that he became a Living Soul, <hi>Gen.</hi> 2. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Where did God place Man in the Begin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the Garden of <hi>Eden,</hi> where he cauſed to grow every Tree that was plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſant to the ſight, and good for Food; the Tree of Life he alſo placed in the midſt of the Garden, and the Tree of Knowlege of Good and Evil, verſ. 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was Man's Work in the Garden?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To dreſs it and keep it, verſ. 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:42947:4"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was Man's Food in the Garden?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Fruit of every Tree of the Gar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>den, except the Fruit of the Tree of Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge of Good and Evil, verſ. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what State was Man placed in the Garden?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In Innocency, not knowing Evil, having liberty to feed of the Tree of Life, and was bleſſed of God in all the Works of his hands.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who gave Names to all Creatures which God had made?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Adam;</hi> and whatſoever he called every Creature, that was the Name there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, verſ. 19, 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was Woman created?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of a Rib which the Lord took out of Man; and ſhe was called Woman, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe ſhe was taken out of Man, <hi>Gen.</hi> 2. 21, 22, 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came Man to loſe that glorious State in which he was created?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By eating of the Fruit of the Tree of Knowledg, which God had forbidden, <hi>Gen.</hi> 3. 17, to the end.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither was</hi> Adam <hi>drove for his Diſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bedience?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Into the Earth, which was curſed for his ſake, <hi>verſ.</hi> 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:42947:4"/>
               <speaker>S,</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was</hi> Adam's <hi>firſt Son, after he was driven into the Earth?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Cain;</hi> who was a Tiller of the Ground <hi>Gen.</hi> 4. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was</hi> Adam<hi>'s ſecond Son?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Abel;</hi> who was a Keeper of Sheep, <hi>Gen.</hi> 4 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why did</hi> Cain <hi>ſlay</hi> Abel <hi>his Brother?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe God had more Reſpect to <hi>Abel</hi> and to his Offering, then to <hi>Cain, Gen.</hi> 4, 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Cain<hi>'s Lot after he had ſlain</hi> Abel?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Curſe from God; being made a Fugative and a Vagabond in the Earth, <hi>Gen.</hi> 4. 11, 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> Adam <hi>live upon the Earth?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Nine Hundred and thirty Years, <hi>Gen.</hi> 5. 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> Seth <hi>live?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M,</speaker>
               <p>Nine hundred and twelve years, <hi>Gen.</hi> 5. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> Enos <hi>live?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Nine hundred and five years, <hi>Gen.</hi> 5. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> Enoch <hi>live?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Three hundred ſixty and five years, <hi>Gen.</hi> 5. 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:42947:5"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> Mathuſalah <hi>live?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Nine hundred ſixty and nine years, <hi>Gen</hi> 5. 27.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What provoked God to deſtroy the old World?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Wickedneſs thereof, <hi>Gen.</hi> 6. 5 6, 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By what did God deſtroy the old World?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By a <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>lood of Water, <hi>Gen.</hi> 6. 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was ſaved from the Flood?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Noah,</hi> and his Houſhold, and all that was with him in the Ark, <hi>Gen.</hi> 7. 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long was the Water upon the Earth?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>An hundred and fifty dayes, <hi>Gen.</hi> 7. 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom did God plant the Earth after the Flood?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Noah,</hi> and his Sons, whom he had bleſſed, <hi>Gen.</hi> 9. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>W<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>t is the Token that God will no more deſtroy <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>e Earth by Water?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>His Bow, which appeareth in the Clouds of Heaven, <hi>Gen.</hi> 9. 13, 14, 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nto whom was the Promiſe of Chriſt to come confirmed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto <hi>Abraham,</hi> and his Seed, which are true Believers, <hi>Gen.</hi> 12. 1, 2, 3. <hi>Gal.</hi> 3. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:42947:5"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nto whom was the Promiſe of the Land of</hi> Canaan?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto <hi>Abraham</hi> and his Seed, <hi>Gen.</hi> 12. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was</hi> Abraham <hi>juſtified?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By Faith in the Promiſe of God, <hi>Gen.</hi> 15. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Token of God's Covenant to</hi> Abraham <hi>and his Seed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Circumciſion in the Fleſh of their Foreskin, <hi>Gen.</hi> 17. 10, 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>With whom was God's everlaſting Cove<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nant eſtabliſhed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>With <hi>Iſaac,</hi> and his Seed after him, <hi>Gen.</hi> 17. 18, 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Sodom <hi>and</hi> Gomorrah <hi>de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe their ſin was very grie<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vous, <hi>Gen.</hi> 19. 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Abraham<hi>'s ſuit to God to ſpare</hi> Sodom?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For the ſake of the Righteous that was in it, <hi>Gen.</hi> 26. to the end.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was found Righteous in the Cities?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Lot, <hi>Gen.</hi> 19. 15. 2 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>With what was</hi> Sodom <hi>and</hi> Gomorrah <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>ſtroyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>With Fire and Brimſtone from Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, <hi>Gen.</hi> 19. 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:42947:6"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who were delivered out of the midſt of the Overthrow?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Lot,</hi> his Wife, and two Daughters, <hi>verſ.</hi> 29.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither did</hi> Lot <hi>go?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To <hi>Zoar, verſ.</hi> 30.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Lot<hi>'s Wife made a Pillar of Salt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe ſhe diſobeyed the Word of the Lord, in looking behind her, <hi>Gen.</hi> 19. <hi>verſ.</hi> 26.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>what Sacrifice did God require of</hi> Abra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ham?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>His only Son <hi>Iſaac, Gen.</hi> 22. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Abraham <hi>bleſſed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe he believed and obeyed God. which was particularly ſhewed in offe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ring his only <hi>Son</hi> at the Command of God, <hi>Gen.</hi> 22. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How old was</hi> Sarah <hi>when ſhe dyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>An hundred and twenty years, <hi>Gen.</hi> 23. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How old was</hi> Abraham <hi>when he dyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>An hundred threeſcore and fifteen years, <hi>Gen.</hi> 25. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was</hi> Abraham<hi>'s Son?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Iſaac,</hi> of whom came <hi>Jacob</hi> and <hi>Eſau, Gen.</hi> 25. 24, 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How many Sons had</hi> Jacob?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:42947:6"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Twelve; <hi>Ruben, Simeon</hi> and <hi>Levi, Judah, Iſachar</hi> and <hi>Zebulun, Joſeph</hi> and <hi>Ben<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jamin, Dan</hi> and <hi>Napthali, Gad</hi> and <hi>Aſher,</hi> Gen. 35. 22, 23, 24, 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Joſeph <hi>hated of his Brethren?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe of the Dream which he drea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>med, <hi>Gen,</hi> 37. 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Joſeph<hi>'s Dream?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That his Brethren's Sheaves did o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beyſance to his Sheaf, <hi>verſ.</hi> 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came</hi> Joſeph <hi>into</hi> Egypt?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He was ſold thither by his Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren for Twenty Pieces of Silver, <hi>Gen.</hi> 37. 28.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was God's End in ſuffering his Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren to ſell him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To preſerve the Lives of many, <hi>Gen.</hi> 45. 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>To whom was</hi> Joſeph <hi>ſold?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To <hi>Potipher,</hi> an Officer of <hi>Pharoah</hi> King of <hi>Egypt.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God try his Heart there?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Temptations of <hi>Potipher</hi>'s Wife, which he with-ſtood, <hi>Gen.</hi> 39. 7, 8, 9, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why did</hi> Potipher <hi>caſt him into Priſon?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe his Wife accuſed him falſly, <hi>Gen.</hi> 39. 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:42947:7"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came</hi> Joſeph <hi>out of Priſon?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Pharoah's</hi> chief Butler, <hi>Gen.</hi> 41. 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came he to be advanced in</hi> Pharoahs <hi>Houſe in</hi> Egypt?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By interpreting <hi>Pharaoh</hi>'s Dream, <hi>Gen.</hi> 41. 38, 39. 40.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Pharoah's <hi>Dream?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That he ſtood by the Bank of a Ri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ver, and there came ſeven fat Kine out of the River, and after them ſeven lean Kine, and the ſeven lean Kine devoured the ſeven fat Kine, &amp;c. <hi>Gen.</hi> 41. 17, 18, 19, 20, 21.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was ſignified by the ſeven fat Kine?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Seven years of great Plenty through<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out all the Land of <hi>Egypt, verſ.</hi> 29.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was ſignified by the ſeven lean Kine?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Seven years of great Famine, ſo that all the Plenty ſhould be forgotten, <hi>verſ.</hi> 30.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did theſe things come to paſs?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, ſo that <hi>Joſeph</hi> having gathered Corn in all the Land of <hi>Egypt,</hi> ſaved many in the Famine, <hi>verſ.</hi> 55, 56.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came</hi> Joſeph<hi>'s Brethren to bow to him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They came down to <hi>Egypt</hi> to buy Corn of him, unto whom they often bow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed,
<pb n="13" facs="tcp:42947:7"/>
not knowing it was their Brother, <hi>Gen.</hi> 42. 6, 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came he to be made known unto them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He diſcovered himſelf, and ſent for his Father into <hi>Egypt,</hi> and nouriſhed him and his Brethren there five years of Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mine, <hi>Gen.</hi> 46. &amp; 47. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Name of the ſecond King over</hi> Egypt?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Pharaoh, <hi>Exod.</hi> 1. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he Rule?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In great Rigour over the Children of <hi>Iſrael, verſ.</hi> 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God deliver Iſrael out of his Hand?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By a ſtrong Hand, and a mighty Pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, <hi>Ex.</hi> 14. 30.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was</hi> Pharaoh <hi>deſtroyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He was drowned in the <hi>Red-Sea, Ex.</hi> 14. 27, 28.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did the Children of Iſrael eſcape through the Red-Sea?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Lord made the Sea a Wall to them on the Right-hand and on the Left, ſo that they walked on Dry Land in the midſt of the ſea, <hi>verſ.</hi> 21, 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither did God bring Iſrael when he de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ivered them out of the Land of</hi> Egypt?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:42947:8"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Into the Wilderneſs of <hi>Sin, Exod.</hi> 16. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>With what did God feed Iſrael in the Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derneſs?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>With Bread from Heaven, <hi>verſ.</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Sabboth God gave Iſrael in the Wilderneſs?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Seventh Day, <hi>verſ.</hi> 22, 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Was Iſrael content with the Bread from Heaven?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; they murmured for want of Water, <hi>Ex.</hi> 17. 2, 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>From whence had they VVater?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Out of the Rock <hi>Horib, Ex.</hi> 17. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was God's Law to Iſrael?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Ten Commandments, &amp;c. <hi>Ex.</hi> 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did Iſrael keep the Law and Command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; for they made a Golden Calf, and worſhipped it, <hi>Ex.</hi> 32. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of the Calf that Iſrael had made?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Moſes burnt it in the Fire, and ground it to Powder, <hi>verſ.</hi> 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither did God lead Iſrael?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Towards the Land of <hi>Canaan,</hi> their Inheritance, <hi>Numb.</hi> 34. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what did Iſrael's Bleſſedneſs conſiſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:42947:8"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In hearkening diligently to the Voice of the Lord their God, and in ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>erving all his Commandments, <hi>Deut.</hi> 28. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what did their miſery ſtand?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In diſobeying the Voice and Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mands of God, <hi>verſ.</hi> 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was God's Purpoſe in giving Iſrael his Law?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they might learn to obſerve the Lord their God, and obſerve and do all the words of the Law, <hi>Deut.</hi> 31. 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom did God give his Law to Iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ael?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Hand of Moſes his Servant, <hi>verſ.</hi> 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How old was</hi> Moſes <hi>when he dyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>An hundred and twenty years, yet his Eyes were not dim, nor his Natural Force abaced, <hi>Deut.</hi> 34. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whom did God chuſe to Rule over Iſrael af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter the Death of</hi> Moſes?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Joſhua</hi> the Son of <hi>Nun, Joſhua</hi> 1. 1, 2, 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S,</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long walked Iſrael in the Wilder<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Forty years, till all the men of War were conſumed, becauſe they obeyed not the Voice of the Lord, <hi>Joſh.</hi> 5. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:42947:9"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Iſrael <hi>ſmitten by their Ene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mies?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe they took of the accurſed Thing, which God had forbidden, <hi>Joſh.</hi> 7. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God manifeſt his Power and Preſence with</hi> Joſhua, <hi>in the behalf of</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In giving him many ſignal Victories over his Enemies. <hi>Joſh.</hi> 6. 20, 21, 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was God's Anger turned away from</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By putting from amongſt them the accurſed thing, which God had forbidden, <hi>Joſh.</hi> 7. 24, 25, 26.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the moſt ſignal Token God ſhew<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed</hi> Joſhua <hi>in the purſuit of his Enemies?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In that he cauſed the Sun and Moon to ſtand ſtill about a whole day at the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>queſt of <hi>Joſhua,</hi> till the People were aven<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ged of their Enemies, <hi>Joſh.</hi> 10. 12, 13, 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How old was</hi> Joſhua <hi>when he dyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>An hundred and ten years old, <hi>Joſh.</hi> 23. 29.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did Iſrael keep the Commandments of the Lord after the Death of</hi> Joſhua?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; they did Evil in the Sight of the Lord, and ſerv'd <hi>Baalim<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> therefore they could no longer ſtand before their Enemies, <hi>Judg.</hi> 2. 11, 12, 13, 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:42947:9"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was Iſrael recovered?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By putting away <hi>Baalim,</hi> and ſer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving the Lord only, 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 2 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God for</hi> Iſrael <hi>when they ſerved<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Deſtroy the <hi>Philiſtines</hi> their Enemies, 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 7. 11, 12, 13, 14</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did</hi> Iſrael <hi>further provoke the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In asking them a King, 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 8. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>To what end did they ask a King?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe the Lord ſhould not raign over the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 8. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the name of the King which</hi> Iſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rael <hi>choſe?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Saul, 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 9. 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom was</hi> Saul <hi>anointed King?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Samuel,</hi> 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 10. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Saul <hi>rejected of God from being King over</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe he kept not God's Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandment, 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 13. 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who did God chuſe to Rule</hi> Iſrael <hi>after</hi> Saul?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>David;</hi> being a Man after his own Heart, <hi>verſ.</hi> 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who anointed</hi> David <hi>King over</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Samuel, 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 16. 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God manifeſt his Power <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> David?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="18" facs="tcp:42947:10"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In ſlaying <hi>Goliah</hi> of the <hi>Philiſtines</hi> without Sword or Spear, 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 17. 37, 38, 39.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>With what did</hi> David <hi>overcome and ſlay</hi> Goliah <hi>of the</hi> Philiſtines?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>With a Sling, and one of the ſmooth Stones taken out of a Brook; and cut off his Head with his own Sword, 1 <hi>Sam,</hi> 17. 40, 49.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God deliver</hi> Saul <hi>to</hi> David?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In a Cave in the Wilderneſs of <hi>Enge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>di,</hi> 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 34. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did</hi> David <hi>kill him in the Cave?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; he had Mercy on him, and only cut off the Lap of his Garment, <hi>verſ.</hi> 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of whom did</hi> Saul <hi>ask Counſel after God was departed from him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of a Witch, 1 <hi>Sam</hi> 28. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did</hi> Saul <hi>dye?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By his own Sword, with his three Sons, 1 <hi>Sam.</hi> 31. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> David <hi>Raign over</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Forty years and ſix Moneths, 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 5. 4, 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what did</hi> David <hi>ſin againſt God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In Committing Adultery with <hi>Bath<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſheba</hi> the Wife of <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>riah</hi> the <hi>Hittite,</hi> 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>1. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who did God ſend to ſhew</hi> David <hi>his ſin?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="19" facs="tcp:42947:10"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Nathan</hi> the Prophet, under the Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>able of the Ewe Lamb, 2 <hi>Sam</hi> 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of the Child</hi> Bathſheba <hi>bare unto</hi> David <hi>in Adultry?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>God ſtruck it that it dyed, 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 12. 18.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came</hi> David <hi>to be reconciled to God again?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By Repentance and great Judgment, <hi>verſ.</hi> 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he offer unto the Lord, who reſtored him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A Song of Praiſe, 2 <hi>Sam.</hi> 22. whole Chapter.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was anointed King over</hi> Iſrael <hi>after</hi> David?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Solomon, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 1. 39.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he ask of God to rule</hi> Iſrael <hi>withal?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Neither Riches nor Honour, but an Underſtanding Heart to do Juſtice and Judgment, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 3. 9, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God anſwer</hi> Solomon<hi>'s Deſire?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In giving him Wiſdom and Under<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtanding exceeding much, and a large Heart, even as the Sand on the Sea-Shore, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 4. 29, 30, 31.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whom did God appoint to build a Houſe for his Name.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="20" facs="tcp:42947:11"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Solomon, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 5. 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Where was the Houſe which</hi> Solomon <hi>built for the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>At <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 7. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did God promiſe his Preſence therein?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, to put his Name there forever, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 9. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Was the Heart of</hi> Solomon <hi>perfect with the Lord, as was</hi> David his <hi>Father?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, he loved the Daughters of <hi>Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ab, Amon</hi> and <hi>Edom,</hi> which the Lord had commanded <hi>Iſrael,</hi> They ſhould not go in to them, nor ſuffer them to come to them, leſt they turned their Hearts after their Godds, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 11. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did</hi> Solomon<hi>'s Wives turn his Heart af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter their Godds?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, ſo that he wrought wicked<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs in the ſight of the Lord, <hi>verſ.</hi> 4, 5 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God manifeſt his diſpleaſure for ſo doing?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In threatning to rent the Kingdom from <hi>Solomon,</hi> and to give it to his Servant, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did God ſpare</hi> Solomon in his Day?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, for <hi>David</hi> his Servant's ſake; but he rent the Kingdom of <hi>Iſrael</hi> out o<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> his Sons Hand, <hi>verſ.</hi> 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="21" facs="tcp:42947:11"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did God rent all the Kingdom of</hi> Iſrael <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ut of the Hand of</hi> Solomon<hi>'s Son?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; he left him one Tribe for <hi>Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vid</hi>'s ſake, and for <hi>Jeruſalem</hi>'s ſake, <hi>verſ.</hi> 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nto whom did God give the ten Tribes of</hi> Iſrael <hi>after</hi> Solomon?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto <hi>Jeroboam</hi> his Servant, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 11, 31.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did</hi> Jeroboam <hi>ſin againſt God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In making two Calves of Gold, ſet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting one in <hi>Bethel,</hi> and the other in <hi>Dan.</hi> and cauſing <hi>Iſrael to worſhip them,</hi> 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 12. 28.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who raigned over</hi> Judah <hi>after</hi> Rehoboam?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Abijam</hi> his Son, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 15. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was he rejected of God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe he walked in the ſins of his Father, <hi>verſ.</hi> 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who Raigned after him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Aſa, <hi>verſ.</hi> 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did</hi> Aſa <hi>walk before God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He did right in the ſight of the Lord, as did <hi>David</hi> his Father, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he pleaſe God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In putting all the <hi>S<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>domites</hi> out of the Land, and putting away the Idols of his Father, <hi>verſ.</hi> 12, 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> Aſa <hi>raign in</hi> Jeruſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="22" facs="tcp:42947:12"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Forty and one Years, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 15. 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who Raigned over</hi> Iſrael <hi>after</hi> Aſa?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Baaſha</hi> the Son of <hi>Ahijah,</hi> 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 15. 33.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did he Raign?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Twenty four years, <hi>verſ.</hi> 33.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he provoke the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In walking in the way of <hi>Jeroboam</hi> his Father, who made <hi>Iſrael</hi> to ſin, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 16. 2, 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who Raigned after</hi> Baaſha <hi>over</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Elah</hi> his Son, <hi>verſ.</hi> 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> Elah <hi>Raign?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Two years, verſ. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who Raigned after</hi> Elah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Zimri;</hi> who ſlew all the Houſe of <hi>Baaſha,</hi> not leaving thereof one to piſs againſt the Wall, according to the Word of the Lord by <hi>Jehu</hi> the Prophet, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 16. 11, 12, 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who Raigned after</hi> Zimri?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Omri,</hi> Captain of the Hoſt, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 16. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he walk before God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He did Evil in the ſight of the Lord, yea, worſe then all that were before him, walking in the ways of <hi>Jeroboam, ver.</hi> 25, 26.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="23" facs="tcp:42947:12"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who raigned over</hi> Iſrael <hi>after</hi> Omri?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Ahab</hi> his Son, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 16. 28.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did he Raign?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Two and twenty years, <hi>verſ.</hi> 29.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he walk before the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He did worſe in the ſight of God then all that was before him, <hi>verſ.</hi> 30.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What were his Sins?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He walked in the way of <hi>Jeroboam</hi> the Son of <hi>Nebat,</hi> who provoked the Lord with their ſins.</p>
               <p>Alſo, he took <hi>Jezabel</hi> the Daughter of <hi>Et baal</hi> King of <hi>Zidonians</hi> to Wife.</p>
               <p>Alſo, he reared up an Alter to <hi>Baal</hi> in the Houſe of <hi>Baal,</hi> which he built in <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maria.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>And he made a Grove, and provoked the Lord God of <hi>Iſrael</hi> more then all the Kings of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> which were before him<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                  <hi>verſ.</hi> 30, 31, 32, 33.</p>
               <p>Furthermore, he coveted <hi>Naboth</hi>'s Vine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard, and <hi>Jezabel</hi> his Wife cauſed <hi>Naboth</hi> to be ſlain for his Vineyard, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 21. 11, 12, 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was God's Diſpleaſure manifeſted againſt</hi> Ahab?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M,</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Elijah</hi> the Prophet, who told him by the Word of the Lord, That in the
<pb n="24" facs="tcp:42947:13"/>
ſame place where Dogs licked up the blood of <hi>Naboth,</hi> ſhould Dogs lick up even his Blood alſo, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 21. 19, 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of</hi> lezabel <hi>his wife.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Lord ſp<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ke ſaying, The Dogs ſhall eat <hi>Jezabel</hi> by the Wall of <hi>Jezreel, verſe</hi> 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did</hi> Ahab <hi>behave himſelf when the Word of the Lord came againſt him by the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phet</hi> Elijah.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He rent his Clothes, and put Sack<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cloth upon him, and Faſted, and lay in Sackcloth, and went ſoftly; and therefore the Lord ſaid, Becauſe <hi>Ahab</hi> humbled him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf, that he would not bring that evil upon his Houſe in his dayes, but in his Sons days would he bring evil upon his Houſe, 1 <hi>Kin.</hi> 21. 27, 28, 29.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of whom did</hi> Ahab <hi>ask counſel, whether he ſhould go to Battel againſt Rampth Gilead, or not?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of four hundred falſe Prophets, who ſaid, Go up, and the Lord ſhall deliver it into thy hand, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 22. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What ſaid the Lord unto him by the mouth of</hi> Micaiah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That God had appointed Evil againſt <hi>Ahab,</hi> and that he ſhould not return from the Battel in Peace, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 22. 23, 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="25" facs="tcp:42947:13"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of</hi> Micaiah <hi>for this Saying?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Ahab</hi> commanded to put him in the Priſon Houſe till he returned, and feed him with Bread &amp; Water of Affliction, <hi>verſ.</hi> 27.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did</hi> Ahab <hi>return in Peace?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; he was ſlain in the Battle at <hi>Raemoth-Gilead,</hi> and the Doggs licked his Blood, according to the Word of the Lord, 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 21. 19. and 22. 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who raigned after him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Jehoſhaphat</hi> the Son of <hi>Aſa, verſ.</hi> 41.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who raigned after him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Ahaziah</hi> the Son of <hi>Ahab, verſ.</hi> 51.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did</hi> Ahaziah <hi>walk with God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He did Evil in his ſight, and walk<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in the way of his Father, and in the way of <hi>Jeroboam</hi> the Son or <hi>Nebat,</hi> in worſhip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ng of <hi>Baal,</hi> 1 <hi>Kings</hi> 22. 52, 53.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of whom did</hi> Ahaziah <hi>in his Sickneſs ask whether he ſhould live or dye?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of <hi>Baalzebub</hi> the Godd of <hi>Ekron, Kings</hi> 1. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who reproved him for it?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>God by <hi>Elijah</hi> the Prophet, <hi>ver.</hi> 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of whom ought he to have enquired?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of the God of <hi>Iſrael, verſ.</hi> 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did the King of</hi> Samaria <hi>dye at that time?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 1. 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="26" facs="tcp:42947:14"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of</hi> Elijah <hi>the Prophet?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He was taken up into Heaven with a Whilewind, 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 2. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom did God ſpeak to</hi> Iſrael <hi>after</hi> Elijah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Eliſha, verſ.</hi> 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God manifeſt his Power with</hi> Eliſha?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In dividing the Waters of <hi>Jordan,</hi> and healing them, 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 2. 14, 21, 22.</p>
               <p>2dly, In increaſing the Oyl in the Wid<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dow's Pitcher, 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 4. 5, 6.</p>
               <p>3dly, In raiſing the <hi>Shunamite</hi>'s Son to Life, <hi>verſ.</hi> 35.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who anointed</hi> Jehu <hi>King over</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>One of the Children of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phets at the Command of <hi>Eliſha.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God require of him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To ſlay the whole Houſe of <hi>Ahab</hi> according to the Word of the Lord, 1 <hi>King</hi> 21. 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did he fulfil the Word of the Lord here in?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, he ſmote <hi>Jehoram</hi> through hi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Heart, and utterly deſtroyed <hi>Jezabel,</hi> an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> the ſeventy Sons of <hi>Ahab,</hi> 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 9. 2<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 33, 34, 35. and chap. 10. 6, 7. and a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> that remained of the Houſe of <hi>Ahab</hi> i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="27" facs="tcp:42947:14"/>
                  <hi>Samaria,</hi> according to the Word of the Lord, <hi>verſ.</hi> 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did</hi> Jehu <hi>walk before God with a perfect Heart?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; for he departed not from the ſins of <hi>Jeroboam, verſ.</hi> 31.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did God's Love continue ſtill to</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, till they fell into Idolatry, and then he loathed them, and ſent Lyons amongſt them, which devour'd them, 2 <hi>King.</hi> 17. 22, 23, 24, 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Iſrael<hi>'s Idolatry?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Their Idols and Images, which eve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry Nation ſerved, and made, and put them in their High Places, 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 17. 29, 32, 41.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who broke down</hi> Iſrael<hi>'s Images and Groves?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Hezekiah</hi> King of <hi>Judah,</hi> 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>8. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he walk before God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In Truth with a perfect Heart, 2 <hi>King.</hi> 20. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>To whom did</hi> Hezekiah <hi>call for help when <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e was ſick?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto the Lord with Tears, 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>0. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did the Lord anſwer him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="28" facs="tcp:42947:15"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In adding to his dayes fifteen years, <hi>verſ.</hi> 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Sign God gave him that he would heal him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In bringing the Shaddow Ten De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grees backward upon the Dial of <hi>Ahaz,</hi> 2 <hi>Kings</hi> 20. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was King of</hi> India?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aſhuerus, <hi>Eſther</hi> 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who contrived the Deſtruction of</hi> Iſrael <hi>in his day?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Hamon, <hi>Eſth.</hi> 3. 8, 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why did</hi> Hamon <hi>ſeek to Deſtroy the</hi> Jews?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe <hi>Mordecai,</hi> whoſe People they were, would not riſe up before him, no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> bow to him, <hi>Eſt.</hi> 3. 3, 4, 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was</hi> Mordecai <hi>and the</hi> Jews <hi>De<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>livered?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>At the Requeſt of Queen <hi>Eſther, Eſth<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> 7. 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of</hi> Hamon, <hi>who contri<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ved the Deſtruction of</hi> Mordecai <hi>and th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> Jews?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He was Hanged by the Kings Com<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>mandment on the Gallows he had prepare<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> for <hi>Mordecai, verſ.</hi> 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of the</hi> Jews <hi>Enemies</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="29" facs="tcp:42947:15"/>
                  <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ll the Provinces of</hi> A<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>aſhuerus?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They were all deſtroyed at the Kings Commandment, with <hi>Hamon</hi>'s Ten Sons, <hi>Eſth.</hi> 9. 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what Land did</hi> Job <hi>dwell?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the Land of <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>z, Job</hi> 1. <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he walk before God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>With a Perfect and Upright Heart, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>earing God, and eſchewing Evil, <hi>verſ.</hi> 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God try his Heart?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>With the Loſs of all his Sons and Daughters, and outward Subſtance, which was great, <hi>verſ.</hi> 15, 16, 17, 18.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did</hi> Job <hi>murmur againſt God, when he ſuffered him to be ſtript of all?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, he did not ſin, nor charge God fooliſhly; but ſaid, The Lord giveth, and the Lord taketh away, bleſſed be the Name of the Lord, <hi>verſ.</hi> 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God further try</hi> Job<hi>'s Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>grity?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>in ſuffering Satan to ſmite his Body from the Crown of his Head to the Sole of his Foot, <hi>Job</hi> 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did not</hi> Job <hi>continue his Integrity to the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yes; neither hitherto did he ſin with his Lips, <hi>verſ.</hi> 3, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="30" facs="tcp:42947:16"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How far did the Lord ſuffer Satan to try</hi> Job?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In all that he had, except his Life <hi>Job</hi> 2. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Could all his Friends and Acquaintanc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> move him from his Integrity?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; though his Wife and Acquain<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tance tempted him on every ſide, <hi>Job</hi> 2. 3 9, 10, 11, 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did God ever reſtore</hi> Job <hi>unto his former Subſtance again?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, in greater abundance then when he firſt ſmote him, <hi>Job</hi> 42. 12, 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> Job <hi>live after God reſtored him to Proſperity in his Subſtance?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Till he ſaw his Sons, and Sons Sons even four Generations, <hi>verſ.</hi> 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who wrote the Book of the Pſalms?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Chiefly <hi>David, Pſal.</hi> 1, 2, 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the Sabſtance of that whol<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> Book?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A Teſtimony of the Prayers, Tears Sufferings and Joys of <hi>David.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Book of the</hi> Proverbs?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Solomon.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the ſubſtance of that Book?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Expreſſions of Wiſdom ſet forth by <hi>Solomon</hi> in many true Proverbs and wi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> Sayings.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="31" facs="tcp:42947:16"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who wrote the Book of</hi> Eccleſiaſtes?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Solomon</hi> the Preacher.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the ſubſtance of that Book?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>It ſetteth forth the Vanity of all <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hings below the Sun, <hi>Eccl.</hi> 1. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the ſubſtance of</hi> Solomon<hi>'s Song?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Such familiar Diſcourſe of Love as in the beſt ſenſe may import myſtical Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>munication of the pure and ſpiritual Love between Chriſt and his Church, <hi>Eccl.</hi> cap. 1, &amp;c.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Book of</hi> Iſaiah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>It was the Viſion of <hi>Iſaiah</hi> the Son of <hi>Amoz,</hi> which he ſaw concerning the Rebellion and Diſobedience of <hi>Judah</hi> and <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> in the dayes of the ſeveral Kings thereof, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was their Diſobedience and Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bellion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Their Princes were Companions of Thieves, whoſe hands were full of Blood; they judged not the Cauſe of the Father<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leſs, nor the Cauſe of the Widdow; but every one loved Gifts, and followed after Rewards, <hi>verſ.</hi> 15, 16, 23, 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Iſaiah <hi>further ſee concerning the</hi> Jews <hi>Rebellion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="32" facs="tcp:42947:17"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they ſhould be as an Oak whoſe Leaf faded, and as a Garden that had no Water, and the ſtrong ſhould be as Tow, and the Maker thereof as a Spark, and they ſhould both burn toge<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther, and none ſhould quench them, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 1. 30, 31.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What People or Nation did God call after the</hi> Jews?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The <hi>Gentiles, Iſa.</hi> chap. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who did God pr<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>miſe to be their Light <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>nd Leader?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Chriſt, the Prince of Peace, <hi>verſ.</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was God's promiſe in him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That in the laſt days the Mountain of the Lord's Houſe ſhould be eſtabliſhed on the top of the Mountains; and many People ſhould ſay, Come, let us walk up to the Mountain of the Lord, to the Houſe of the God of <hi>Jacob,</hi> and he will teach us of his Wayes, &amp;c. <hi>Iſa.</hi> 2. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Iſaiah<hi>'s Viſion concerning Wars after Chriſt's Coming?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they ſhould beat their Swords into Mattocks, and their Spears into Sythes, and Nation ſhall no more lift up a Sword againſt Nation, neither ſhould learn War any more.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="33" facs="tcp:42947:17"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did</hi> Iſaiah <hi>ſet forth the State of</hi> Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dah <hi>and</hi> Jeruſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Under the ſimilitude of a Vineyard, which was hedged about, and planted with choyce Plants, and p<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>a<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ed in a very fruit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ful Hill, from which the Planter expect<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Grapes, but it brought forth wild Grapes, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 5. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Sentence given againſt this <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>uitleſs Vineyard?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To take away the Hedge thereof, that it may be eaten up; and break down the Wall thereof, that it may be trodden down; and to lay it waſte, &amp;c. <hi>Iſa.</hi> 5. <hi>verſ.</hi> 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who did God promiſe to the Remnant of</hi> Judah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Chriſt, the <hi>Immanuel, Iſa.</hi> 7. 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God promiſe to the</hi> Gentiles?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they who walked in Darkneſs had ſeen great Light, and they who dwelt in the Land of the ſhaddow of Death upon them had the Light ſhined, <hi>Iſa</hi> 9. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of whom did Chriſt ſpring?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Out of the Stem of <hi>Jeſſe, Iſa.</hi> 11. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Iſaiah<hi>'s Viſion concerning</hi> Ba<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bylon?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="34" facs="tcp:42947:18"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That it ſhould be deſtroyed by the <hi>Meeds</hi> and <hi>Perſians, Iſa.</hi> 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>D<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>d God return the Captivity of</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, and made them reſt in their own Land; and ſaid, they ſhould take them Priſoners whoſe Captives they were, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 14. 1, 2 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Iſaiah <hi>ſee concerning</hi> Moab?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Its Deſtruction, becauſe of its Pride and Arrogancy, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 16. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was Propheſied concerning</hi> Damaſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cus <hi>and</hi> Ephraim?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Their Deſtruction and Overthrow, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 17. 1, 2, 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Iſaiah<hi>'s Sign in going Naked three Years?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The three years Captivity of <hi>Egypt</hi> and <hi>Ethiopia, Iſa.</hi> 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was promiſed by Chriſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Remiſſion of Sins, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 40. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>When was the Coming of</hi> John Baptiſt <hi>ſeen?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the days of <hi>Iſaiah. verſ.</hi> 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his Work?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To prepare the Way of the Lord, <hi>v.</hi> 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was Chriſt ſent a Light into the World?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For a Covenant to the people, and
<pb n="35" facs="tcp:42947:18"/>
for a Light to the <hi>Gentiles,</hi> to open the Eyes of the Blind, and to bring the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>riſoners out of the Priſon-Houſe, and them that ſit in Darkneſs out of the region of the ſhaddow of Death, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 42 6, 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Iſaiah <hi>ſee concerning</hi> Babylon?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Deſtruction thereof, and of their Idols, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 47.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was God's Promiſe to the</hi> Gentile<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That more of them ſhould believe the Goſpel, then the <hi>Jews, Iſa.</hi> 54. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was God's Invitation to the Thirſty under the Goſpel?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To come to the Water of Life and drink freely, without Money and without Price, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 55. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Wherefore did he reprove the</hi> Jews?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For ſpending their Money for that which was not bread, and their Labour for that which did not ſatisfie, <hi>verſ.</hi> 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he ſee concerning the Watchmen of</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M</speaker>
               <p>That they were all blind, and had no knowledge, and that they were dumb and greedy Dogs, that could never have enough every one lo<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>king for their own <hi>wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                     <g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> &amp; for his Gain from his Quarter. <hi>Iſa</hi> 56. 10, 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>To what did</hi> Iſaiah <hi>compare the Wicked?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="36" facs="tcp:42947:19"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To the raging Sea, whoſe Waters caſt up Mire and Dirt, <hi>Iſa.</hi> 57. 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Hypocrites Faſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To afflict his Soul for a day, and to hang down his head as a Bulruſh, <hi>Iſ.</hi> 58. 4<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Faſt of the Faithful?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To looſe the hands of Wickedneſs, to take off the heavy Burdens, and to let the Oppreſſed go free, <hi>verſ.</hi> 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the chief Subſtance of the Book of</hi> Iſaiah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>An Evangeligal Propheſie of the Coming, Work, and Power of Chriſt, with God's Univerſal Love in Chriſt to all Mankind?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>When came the Word of the Lord to</hi> Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>remiah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the dayes of <hi>Joſiah</hi> King of <hi>Ju<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dah, Jer.</hi> 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the firſt Sign God ſhewed</hi> Jere<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miah <hi>of the Deſtruction of</hi> Judah <hi>and</hi> Jeruſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Rod of an Almon Tree its ear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly budding, ſhewing that God would ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ten to perform his Word, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the next Sign given</hi> Jeremiah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A Seething-Pot out of the North, thorough which God declared to them his
<pb n="37" facs="tcp:42947:19"/>
Judgments, for all the Wickedneſs of them that forſook him, &amp; burnt Incenſe to other Godds, and worſhipped the Works of their own hands, <hi>verſ.</hi> 13, 14, 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Jeruſalem <hi>deſtroyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe they forſook the Lord, the Fountain of living Waters, and digged to th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>mſelves broken Ciſterns, that would hold no Water, <hi>Jer.</hi> 2. 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God ſet forth</hi> Iſrael<hi>'s Reblelion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>As a Woman that Rebelleth againſt her Husband, ſo did the whole Houſe of <hi>Iſrael</hi> Rebel againſt God, <hi>Jer.</hi> 3. 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What Circumciſion more then the outward did the Lord require of the Men of</hi> Judah <hi>and</hi> Jeruſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Circumciſion of the Heart<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> 
                  <hi>Jer.</hi> 4. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Egypt, Judah, Edom, <hi>and the Children of</hi> Amon <hi>threatned by the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe they were not Circumciſed in Heart, <hi>Jer.</hi> 9. 26.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What Figure did God give</hi> Jeremiah <hi>of the Deſtruction of the</hi> Jews?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A Linnen Girdle, which God cauſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>e<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> him to hide in the Clift of the Rock <hi>Pe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rath, Jer.</hi> 13. 4, 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What were the Plagues with which God would deſtroy the</hi> Jews?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="38" facs="tcp:42947:20"/>
               <speaker>M</speaker>
               <p>Four; the Sword to ſlay, the Dogs t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>ar, the Fowl<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>s of the Heaven and the Beaſts of the Earth to devour, <hi>Jer.</hi> 15 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom did God then declare his Will and Mind to t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e</hi> Jews?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Jeremiah,</hi> for which the <hi>Jews</hi> con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpir'd Miſchief againſt him, <hi>Jer.</hi> 18. 18.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who ſmote</hi> Jeremiah, <hi>and put him in the Stocks, for ſpeak<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ng the Word of the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paſhur</hi> the Son of <hi>Immer</hi> the Prieſt, <hi>Jer.</hi> 20. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Jeremiah <hi>teſtifie concerning the falſe Paſtors of</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M</speaker>
               <p>He cry'd Wo unto them who deſtroy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and ſcatt<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>red the Sheep of the Lord's Paſture, <hi>Jer.</hi> 23. 1, 2.</p>
               <p>He cry'd alſo againſt the Prophets of <hi>Sa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maria,</hi> that propheſi<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>d in <hi>Baal,</hi> and cauſed the people to err, <hi>verſ.</hi> 13.</p>
               <p>He alſo cryed againſt the Prophets of <hi>Je<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruſalem,</hi> who committed Adultery, and w<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>lked in Lyes, and ſtrengthened the hands of Evil-doers, ſo that none could turn from his Wickedneſs; that they were all as <hi>So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom,</hi> and as the Inhabitants of <hi>Gomorrah, verſ.</hi> 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>whom did the Lord promiſe to ſet over his flock?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="39" facs="tcp:42947:20"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Chriſt the true Shepherd, <hi>Jer.</hi> 23 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Cauſe the falſe Prophets of</hi> Iſrael <hi>did not profit the people?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe they ſtood not in the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel of God themſelves, therefore was not the Word of the Lord with them, neither did they profit the people at all, <hi>verſ.</hi> 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God threaten to bring upon</hi> Judah <hi>and</hi> Jeruſalem <hi>for their continued Rebellion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they ſhould be in Captivity under the King of <hi>Babylon</hi> Seventy Years, <hi>Jer.</hi> 25. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did the falſe Prophets of</hi> Iſrael <hi>deal with</hi> Jeremy <hi>for ſpeaking the Word of the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They judged him worthy of Death, <hi>Jer.</hi> 26. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God command</hi> Jeremiah <hi>to ſend unto the King of</hi> Judah, <hi>and the other Kings near him, to premoniſh them of their Captivity under</hi> Nebuchadnezar?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Bonds and Yoaks, <hi>Jer.</hi> 27. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>When was</hi> Judah <hi>and</hi> Jeruſalem <hi>brought into Captivity under the King of</hi> Babel?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the Beginning of the Raign of <hi>Jehoiakim</hi> the Son of <hi>Joſiah</hi> King of <hi>Judah, Jer.</hi> 26. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>When did God promiſe their Return?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>After Seventy Years, <hi>Jer.</hi> 29. 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="40" facs="tcp:42947:21"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Promiſe of God to</hi> Iſrael <hi>af<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter their Return?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>His Everlaſting Love and Mercy to them, in making a New Covenant with them. <hi>Jer.</hi> 31. 31.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was that New Covenant?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To write his Law in their Hearts, and place his Fear in their inward parts, that they ſhould no more teach every man his Brother, &amp;c. <hi>verſ.</hi> 33, 34.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God further promiſe</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That he would give them one Heart and one Way, <hi>Jer.</hi> 32. 39.</p>
               <p>Alſo, That he would cauſe the Branch of Righteouſneſs to ſpring up unto <hi>David,</hi> who ſhould execute Judgment and Righteouſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs in the Land, <hi>Jer.</hi> 33. 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was King in</hi> Judah <hi>when the King of</hi> Babylon <hi>came to deſtroy</hi> Ieruſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Zedekiah, Jer.</hi> 34. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Ieremiah <hi>put into the Stocks, and into the miery Dungeon?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For ſpeaking the word of the Lord concerning the Deſtruction of <hi>Jeruſalem? Jer.</hi> 38. 4, 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was</hi> Ieremiah <hi>deliverod out of the Dungeon?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the interceſſion of <hi>Ebed-Mele<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>h,</hi>
                  <pb n="41" facs="tcp:42947:21"/>
the <hi>Black-moor</hi> to the King, <hi>Jer.</hi> 38. 9, 10, 11, 12, 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Where did</hi> Ieremiah <hi>remain then?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the Court of the Priſon, <hi>Jer.</hi> 38. 28.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long continued he there?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Till <hi>Jeruſalem was taken by the King of</hi> Babel, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11, 12, 13, 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who freed</hi> Ieremiah <hi>out of Priſon?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Nebuzaraden,</hi> the chief Steward of the King of <hi>Babylon, Jer.</hi> 40. 1, 2, 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of the</hi> Iews <hi>that were in</hi> Egypt?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They were deſtroyed by the Word of the Lord <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> their Idolatry there, <hi>Jer.</hi> 46. 9, 10, 11 <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> Moab, <hi>and his Cities?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                  </gap>, and his Cities burnt up, <hi>J<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                        <desc>••</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>mon, Edom <hi>and</hi> Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maſcus?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They were <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>l laid waſte, <hi>Jer.</hi> 49.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Ieremiah <hi>Propheſie concerning</hi> Babylon?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Its Deſtruction, and the Delive<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rance of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> which was in Captivity, <hi>Jer.</hi> 50.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Babylon <hi>deſtroyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="42" facs="tcp:42947:22"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For the Iniquity and Idolatry there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of, <hi>Jer.</hi> 51.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what Year of</hi> Zedekiah<hi>'s Raign wa<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> Jeruſalem <hi>beſieged by the King of</hi> Babylon?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the ninth Year, in the tenth Mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neth, the tenth day of the Month, <hi>Jer.</hi> 52. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long was</hi> Jeruſalem <hi>beſieged?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Until the 11th year of his raign <hi>Jer.</hi> 52. 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>When was the City broken up?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the 4th moneth the 9th day. <hi>ver.</hi> 6, 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of</hi> Zedekiah, <hi>and his Sons, and all the Princes of</hi> Judah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The King of <hi>Babel</hi> took <hi>Zedekiah,</hi> and put out his Eyes, and bound him in Chains, and carried him to <hi>Babel,</hi> and put him in Priſon to the day of his death, and ſlew his Sons before his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap>, and all the Princes of <hi>Judah, verſ.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of the <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> of the Lord in</hi> Jeruſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Both the Houſe of the Lord and the King's Houſe, and all the Houſes of <hi>Jeru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſalem</hi> did <hi>Nabuzaradan,</hi> the chief Steward of the King of <hi>Babylon,</hi> burn with Fire, and brake down all the Walls of the City round about, <hi>verſ,</hi> 13, 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the ſubſtance of the</hi> Lamenta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions <hi>of</hi> Jeremiah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="43" facs="tcp:42947:22"/>
               <speaker>M</speaker>
               <p>To ſet forth the miſerable ſtate of <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> in the Land of <hi>Judah,</hi> for the mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titude of their Trangreſſions, <hi>Lam.</hi> 1, 2, 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>To whom was</hi> Ezekiel <hi>ſent to Propheſie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto the <hi>Children of Iſrael</hi> in Capti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vity, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 3, 4, 5, 6,</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was propheſied concerning them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That God would ſpare a Remnant from the Sword, Famine and Peſtilence, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 6. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was to be ſpared in the Overthrow of</hi> Jeruſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>All thoſe whom <hi>Ezekiel</hi> was comman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded to mark, who mourn'd and cry'd for the Abominations that were done in the midſt thereof, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 9. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nto what did</hi> Ezekiel <hi>liken the falſe Prophets of</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>Unto Foxes in waſte places, <hi>Eze.</hi> 13. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was their Error?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M</speaker>
               <p>In ſlaying the ſouls of them that ſhould live, and giving life to them that ſhould dye, <hi>verſ.</hi> 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Tyrus <hi>deſtroyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe of its Pride and Preſumpti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, <hi>Ezek</hi> 28. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Zidon <hi>laid waſte?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe of the multitude of its Abo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minations, <hi>verſ.</hi> 22, 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="44" facs="tcp:42947:23"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Ezekiel <hi>further teſtifie againſt the falſe Prophets of</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they eat the Fat, and cloathed with the Wooll, and killed thoſe that were fed, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 34. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Ezekiel <hi>Propheſie concerning</hi> Mount Seir?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That it ſhould be laid deſolate, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cauſe the Inhabitants thereof troubled the People of the Lord, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 35. 4, 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nto what was the Children of</hi> Iſrael <hi>liken<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed in their Captivity?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto dry Bones in an open Valley, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 37. 1, 2, 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God do for them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He cauſed them to come together Bone to his Bone, and brought Fleſh upon them, and breathed Life into them, and they became the whole Houſe of <hi>Iſrael, Eze.</hi> 37. 10, 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God further promiſe to them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To make them one People, and ſet up one Shepherd over them, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 37. 22, 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was the firſt that ſhould fight againſt the</hi> Iſrael <hi>of God, after their Restauration?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Gogg</hi> and <hi>Magogg, Ezek.</hi> 38 <hi>verſ<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
                  </hi> 16, 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="45" facs="tcp:42947:23"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Ezekiel <hi>propheſie concerning them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That God would deſtroy them, and their great Armies, wherewith they fight againſt <hi>Iſrael, Ezek.</hi> 39. 2, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Ezekiel <hi>ſee concerning the Tem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple and City of</hi> Ieruſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They ſhould be reſtored and built a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 40.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did the Glory of God return to the Temple?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the Viſion of <hi>Ezekiel,</hi> he ſaw the Glory of the Lord come out of the Eaſt, and came into the Temple, whoſe proſpect was towards the Eaſt, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 43. 2, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was</hi> Iſrael <hi>Reproved of the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For bringing into the Sanctuary of the Lord the Uncircumciſed in Heart and Fleſh, <hi>Ezek.</hi> 44. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who did God chuſe after</hi> Ezekiel <hi>to bear witneſs of Him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Daniel, Shadrach, Meſhach, and A<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bednego, <hi>Dan.</hi> 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was King of</hi> Babylon <hi>in the days of</hi> Daniel?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Nebuchadnezar, <hi>Dan.</hi> 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God manifeſt his Power and Wiſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom through</hi> Daniel?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="46" facs="tcp:42947:24"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In interpreting <hi>Nebuchadnezzar</hi>'s Dream, which all the Wiſe-men of <hi>Babylon</hi> could not do, <hi>verſ.</hi> 9, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God manifeſt his Power with</hi> Shadrach, Meſhach <hi>and</hi> Abednego?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In delivering them out of the midſt of the burning Furnace, <hi>Dan.</hi> 3. 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom were they caſt in and for what?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Nebuchadnezzar</hi> King of <hi>Babylon,</hi> for refuſing to bow down to the Image he had ſet up, <hi>verſ.</hi> 26.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Nebuchadnezzar<hi>'s Dream?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Concerning a great Tree and ſtrong, whoſe height reached to Heaven, and the ſight thereof to the Ends of the Earth, &amp;c. <hi>Dan.</hi> 4. 10, 11, 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>L.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did this great Tree ſignifie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The King <hi>Nebuchadnezzar, verſ.</hi> 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did the Fall thereof ſignifie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The fall of the King of <hi>Babel, ver.</hi> 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who Interpreted</hi> Nebuchadnezzar<hi>'s Dream?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Daniel;</hi> who warned him to break off his Sins by Repentance, and his Ini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quities by ſhewing Mercy to the Poor, <hi>verſe</hi> 27.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did he hearken to</hi> Daniel<hi>'s Counſel?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, and therefore his Kingdom was
<pb n="47" facs="tcp:42947:24"/>
rent from him, and he was driven from Man, and did eat Graſs as Oxen, and his Body was wet with the Dew of Heaven, till his Hairs were like Eagles Feathers, and his Nailes like Birds Claws, <hi>verſe</hi> 33.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was King of</hi> Babylon <hi>after him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Belſhazzer</hi> his Son, <hi>Dan.</hi> 5. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did he deſpiſe the Idols of his Father?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, he praiſed them, <hi>verſe</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God appear againſt him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He cauſed the Fingers of a Man's Hand to appear upon the Plaſter of the Wall of the King's Pallace, and to write, Mene, Mene, Tekel, Upharſin, <hi>verſ.</hi> 5. &amp; 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the interpretation theroof?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>1. That God had number'd his King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, and finiſhed it.</p>
               <p>2. That the King was weighed in the Ballance, and found too light.</p>
               <p>3. That his Kingdom was divided, and gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven to the <hi>Medes</hi> and <hi>Perſians, ver.</hi> 26, 27, 28.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was King of</hi> Babylon <hi>after him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Darius, <hi>verſ.</hi> 31.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he for</hi> Daniel?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He preferred him above all the Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernours of his Kingdom, becauſe an exce<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lent Spirit, Light and Underſtanding was found in him, <hi>Dan.</hi> 6. 2, 3. chap. 5. 11, 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="48" facs="tcp:42947:25"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>For what did the Rulers of</hi> Darius <hi>ſeek to deſtroy</hi> Daniel?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For Praying unto his God, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>When they could find no other Fault in him, they cauſed <hi>Darius</hi> to make a De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree, That whoſoever ſhould ask a Petition of any other God or Man, for thirty days, ſave of King <hi>Darius,</hi> ſhould be caſt into the Den of Lyons, <hi>verſ.</hi> 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did</hi> Daniel <hi>condeſcend to the King here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>in?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; for he prayed to his God as at other times, <hi>Dan.</hi> 6. 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Was he caſt into the Den of Lyons for Praying?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea; but the Angel of God ſhut the Lyons Mouthes, that he had no Harm, <hi>verſ.</hi> 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was</hi> Daniel <hi>delivered out of the Den?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Kings Commandment, <hi>Dan.</hi> 6. 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of his Accuſars?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The King commanded them to be caſt into the Den of Lyons, <hi>verſ.</hi> 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Were they preſerved in the Den?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; for the Lyons had Maſtry over
<pb n="49" facs="tcp:42947:25"/>
them and broke all their Bones in pieces ere they came at the Ground of the Den, verſ. 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Daniel<hi>'s next Viſion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Concerning four Beaſts, that aroſe out of the Sea, <hi>Dan.</hi> 7. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the firſt like unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto a Lyon, and had Eagles Wings, and a Man's Heart was given him, <hi>verſ.</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the ſecond Beaſt like unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto a Bear; and it was ſaid unto him, Ariſe, and devour much Fleſh, <hi>verſ.</hi> 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the third Beaſt like unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto a Leoaprd, which had upon his Back f<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ur Wings of a Fowl; and the Beaſt had four Heads, and Dominion was given unto him, <hi>verſ.</hi> 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the fourth Beaſt like unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He was fearful, and terrible, and ve<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry ſtrong, and had great Iron Teeth, who devoured, and brake to pieces, and ſtam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ped the reſidue under his Feet; and was un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like to the Beaſts that were before it; for it had ten Horns, <hi>verſ.</hi> 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Daniel <hi>further ſee?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Ancient of Dayes ſit upon his Throne, whoſe Garment was white as Snow, and the Hair of his Head like pure
<pb n="50" facs="tcp:42947:26"/>
Wool; before whom Ten Thouſand Thou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſands ſtood, and the Judgment was ſet, and the Books open'd, <hi>verſ.</hi> 9, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of the firſt great and ter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rible Beaſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He was ſlain, and his Body deſtroy<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, and given to the Burning Fire, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11. <hi>What became of the other Beaſts?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>their Dominion was taken away, yet their Lives were prolong'd for a ſeaſon, <hi>verſ.</hi> 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did the four Beaſts ſignifie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Four Kings that ſhould ariſe out of the Earth, who ſhould take the Kingdom of the Saints of the Moſt High, and ſhould make War againſt the Saints, and ſhould prevail againſt them, <hi>verſ.</hi> 17, 18.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long were they to prevail!</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Until the Ancient of Dayes came, and Judgment was given to the Saints of the Moſt High, who ſhould poſſes the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, <hi>Dan.</hi> 7. 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Daniel<hi>'s next Viſion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of a Battle between a Ram and a Goat, <hi>Dan.</hi> 8. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did the Ram with his two Horns ſignifie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Kings of the <hi>Meeds</hi> and <hi>Perſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans, verſ.</hi> 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="51" facs="tcp:42947:26"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did the Goat ſignifie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The King of <hi>Grecia, verſe</hi> 21.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was ſignified by the puſhing of the Ram every way, ſo that no Beaſt could ſtand before him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The great Power and ſtrength of the Kings of the <hi>Meeds</hi> and <hi>Perſians, verſ.</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was ſignified by the Horn that ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>peared between the Goat's Eyes, with which he deſtroyed the Ram?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The firſt King of <hi>Grecia,</hi> who was to ſubdue the King of the <hi>Meeds</hi> and <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſians,</hi> and ſtamp them under his Feet, ſo that none could deliver them out of his Power, <hi>Dan.</hi> 8. 21.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Againſt whom did the Goat bend his ſtrength?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Againſt the Mighty and Holy Peo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ple, and againſt the Prince of Princes; but he was to be broken without hands, <hi>verſ.</hi> 24, 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Daniel<hi>'s Petition to God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To return the Captivity of <hi>Iſrael</hi> out of <hi>Babylon,</hi> Dan. 9. 16, 17, 18.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Daniel<hi>'s next Viſion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of the Appearance of the Son of Man, <hi>Dan.</hi> 10. 5, 6, 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he ſhew to</hi> Daniel?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>All the Kingdoms<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> which ſhould be
<pb n="52" facs="tcp:42947:27"/>
Enemies to the Church of God, as of <hi>Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſia, Greece,</hi> of <hi>Aegypt, Syria,</hi> and of the <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mans, Dan.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the End of all theſe Kings, and what was promiſed to the Church of Christ?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Deſtruction to themſelves, and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liverance to the Juſt, with the Reſurrecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on thereof. and of the Un juſt, <hi>Dan.</hi> 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of what did</hi> Hoſea <hi>Propheſie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of the Calling of the <hi>Gentiles,</hi> as well as the <hi>Jews;</hi> and that Chriſt ſhould be Head of them all, <hi>Hoſea</hi> 1. 10, 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his Complaint?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That the Land of Iſrael was full of Adulterers; and by Lying, Swearing, Killing, Stealing and Whoring, ſo that Blood toucheth Blood, <hi>Hoſ.</hi> 4. 2.</p>
               <p>2dly, That their Prieſts and Rulers had been as a Snare to <hi>Miſpah,</hi> and a Net ſpread upon <hi>Tabor, Hoſea</hi> 5. 1.</p>
               <p>3dly, That as Troops of Robbers wait for a man, ſo the Company of Prieſts Murder in the way by Conſent; for they commit Lewdneſs, <hi>Hoſ.</hi> 6. 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the ſubſtance of</hi> Hoſea<hi>'s Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phecy?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To demonſtrate the Abominations and Miſeries of <hi>Iſrael, Aegypt</hi> and <hi>Ephraim;</hi>
                  <pb n="53" facs="tcp:42947:27"/>
and how the Lord would utterly caſt them off in his Wrath, <hi>Hoſ.</hi> 8. &amp; 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Joel<hi>'s Propheſie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Againſt the <hi>Jews,</hi> whom he exhor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted to Prayer and faſting, for the Miſery that was at hand, <hi>Joel</hi> 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did the Lord promiſe by the Mouth of</hi> Joel <hi>in the latter dayes?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To pour out his Spirit upon all Fleſh; that his Sons and Daughters ſhould Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pheſie, &amp;c. <hi>Jo.</hi> 2. 28.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Subſtance of the Prophecy of</hi> Amos?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The denouncing of God's continu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed Judgments upon <hi>Iſrael, Judah, Tyrus, Edom</hi> and <hi>Amon,</hi> for their continued Abo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>minations, <hi>Amos</hi> 1, 2, 3. chap.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of what Calling was</hi> Amos?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>An Herdſman, <hi>Amos</hi> 1. 1. &amp; 7. 14?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>For what was the Lamentation of</hi> Amos.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For the Captivity of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> Amos 5?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God ſignifie by a Line to</hi> Amos.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Deſtruction of the People <hi>Iſra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>el,</hi> Amos 7. 7, 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God further ſhew to</hi> Amos <hi>con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A Famine amongſt them of the Word of the Lord, for their Rebellion, <hi>Amos</hi> 8. 11, 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="54" facs="tcp:42947:28"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was God's Promiſe to his Church in thoſe dayes?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Its Reſtauration; ſo that the Plow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man ſhould reach the Mower<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>, and the Treader of Grapes him that ſoweth Seed, &amp;c. <hi>Amos</hi> 9. 11, 12, 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Viſion of</hi> Obad iah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Word of the Lord againſt <hi>E<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom,</hi> and its Inhabitants, who were of the ſtock of <hi>Eſau,</hi> Obad. 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Word of the Lord concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Againſt their Pride and High-min<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dedneſs, in exalting themſelves againſt the Seed of <hi>Jacob,</hi> Obad. 3. 8, 9, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Word of the Lord to</hi> Jonah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To go and preach Repentance to <hi>Nineveth,</hi> the chief City of the <hi>Aſſyrians,</hi> Jonah 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Was</hi> Jonah <hi>obedient to the Word of the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; for he fled to <hi>Tarſhiſh,</hi> from the Preſence of the Lord, <hi>verſ.</hi> 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God ſtop his way?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By a mighty Tempeſt at Sea, <hi>verſ.</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was it known that</hi> Jonah <hi>was the Cauſe why the Ship was in Danger to be loſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Lots which the Marriner<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>
                  <pb n="55" facs="tcp:42947:28"/>
caſt, to know for whoſe Cauſe that great Tempeſt was in the Sea, <hi>verſ.</hi> 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was the Tempeſt in the Sea aſwaged?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By caſting of <hi>Jonah</hi> into the Sea, <hi>v.</hi> 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By what was</hi> Jonah <hi>preſerved in the Sea?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By a Whale, which God had prepa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red to ſwallow him up, who, at the Word of the Lord caſt <hi>Jonah</hi> upon the dry Land, <hi>Jonah</hi> 1. 17. &amp; 2. 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither did God ſend</hi> Jonah <hi>afterwards?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To <hi>Nineveth,</hi> Jonah 3. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did he obey the Word of the Lord the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond time?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, and went a dayes Journey into <hi>Nineveth,</hi> and cry'd, Yet Forty Days and <hi>Nineveth</hi> ſhall be deſtroyed, <hi>verſe</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did the King, and People of</hi> Nineveth, <hi>Repent at the Preaching of</hi> Jonah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, and turned from their Evil Wayes, ſo that God repented of the Evil that he had intended againſt them, and he did it not, <hi>verſ.</hi> 8, 9, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of what did</hi> Micah <hi>Propheſie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of the Deſtruction of <hi>Judah</hi> and <hi>Iſrael,</hi> becauſe of their Idolatry, <hi>Mic.</hi> 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Iniquity of the Princes and Prieſts of</hi> Judah <hi>and</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Heads thereof judged for Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wards,
<pb n="56" facs="tcp:42947:29"/>
and the Prieſts thereof taught for Hire, &amp;c. <hi>Mic.</hi> 3. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did God Promiſe in the latter dayes?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Eſtabliſhment of the Kingdom of Chriſt, and felicity of his Church, <hi>Mic.</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nto what did</hi> Micah <hi>liken the beſt of the Houſe of</hi> Iſrael?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto a Bryar, and the moſt pure a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt them ſharper then a Thorn Hedge, <hi>Mic.</hi> 7. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of what did</hi> Nahum <hi>Propheſie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of the Deſtruction of the <hi>Aſſyrians,</hi> and the Deliverance of <hi>Iſrael,</hi> Nahum 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of their chief City</hi> Nine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>veh?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>It was deſtroy'd, becauſe of the mul<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>titude of its Forninations, <hi>Nahum</hi> 3. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Habbakkuk<hi>'s Complaint?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Againſt the Wicked that perſecuted the Juſt, <hi>Hab.</hi> 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Prophecy of</hi> Zepheniah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Againſt <hi>Judah</hi> and <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> for their Idolatry, Zeph. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the ſubſtance of the Prophecy of</hi> Haggai, Zacheriah <hi>and</hi> Malachi?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They were raiſed up to Comfort the <hi>Jews,</hi> after the ſeventy years of their Cap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tivity
<pb n="57" facs="tcp:42947:29"/>
was ended, to exhort them to build the Temple again; which was a Figure of the ſpiritual Temple and Church of God, whoſe Perfection and Excellency ſtood in Chriſt, <hi>Hag.</hi> 1, 2. cap. <hi>Zach.</hi> 1, 2, 3. cap.</p>
               <p>2ly, To call the <hi>Jews</hi> home to <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> by the Word of the Lord, and to make them a Bleſſing.</p>
               <p>3ly, The calling of the <hi>Gentiles,</hi> and the coming of Chriſt, <hi>Zach.</hi> 8, 9. cap.</p>
               <p>4ly, The coming of <hi>John Baptist,</hi> who was to prepare the Way of the Lord, <hi>Mal.</hi> 3. 1.</p>
               <p>5ly, Of the coming of the great and ter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rible <hi>day</hi> of the Lord, wherein all the Proud, and all that did wickedly, ſhould be as ſtub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble, before which <hi>Eliah</hi> the Prophet ſhould come, <hi>Mal.</hi> 4. 1, 5.</p>
            </sp>
         </div>
         <div type="catechism">
            <pb n="58" facs="tcp:42947:30"/>
            <head>
               <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pon the New-Teſtament.</head>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>VVHO wrote the firſt Book of the New-Teſtament in the Bible?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Matthew.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What doth it contain?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Geneology of Chriſt, the Time and Place of his Birth, his Suf<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferings, Temptations, Baptiſm, and Doctrine, <hi>Mat.</hi> 1. 2, 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Where was Chriſt born, and of whom was he baptized?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He was born of a pure Virgin, who was eſpouſed to <hi>Joſeph,</hi> being found with Child of the Holy Ghoſt, <hi>verſ.</hi> 18.</p>
               <p>2dly, Chriſt was baptized of <hi>John</hi> in <hi>Jordan,</hi> Mat. 3. 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was the first King that ſought to deſtroy Chriſt after his Birth?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="59" facs="tcp:42947:30"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Herod,</hi> Mat. 2. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he eſcape</hi> Herod's <hi>hand?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Angel of God appeared to <hi>Joſeph</hi> in a Dream, and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manded him to take the Young Child, and flee into <hi>Egypt,</hi> who re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mained there till the Death of <hi>Herod, verſ.</hi> 13, 14, 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the firſt Temptation which Chriſt ſuſtained from the Devil?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>After he had faſted Forty Days, he tempted him, to command Stones to be made Bread, <hi>Mat.</hi> 4. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his ſecond Temptation?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To caſt himſelf down from the Pinacle of the Temple, <hi>verſ.</hi> 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his third Temptation?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To fall down and worſhip the Devil, <hi>verſ.</hi> 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he overcome the Evil One?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By reſiſting his Temptations by the Power of God, in which he ſtood, <hi>verſ.</hi> 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="60" facs="tcp:42947:31"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was the Power of God mani<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſted to the World through him by Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racles?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>1ſt, In healing the Sick of the Palſie, <hi>Mat.</hi> 9, 2.</p>
               <p>2ly, In healing of the Woman who had a Bloody-Iſſue, <hi>verſ.</hi> 22.</p>
               <p>3ly, In raiſing <hi>Jara</hi>'s Daughter to Life, <hi>ver.</hi> 25.</p>
               <p>4ly, In reſtoring the Blind to ſight, <hi>ver.</hi> 29, 30.</p>
               <p>5ly, In making the Dumb to ſpeak, and healing every Sickneſs, <hi>verſ.</hi> 33, 34, 35.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom was the Twelve Apoſtles ſent out?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By Chriſt; who gave them Power againſt unclean ſpirits, to caſt them out, and to heal every Sickneſs, <hi>Mat.</hi> 10. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Unto what did Christ liken the Kingdom of Heaven?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto a man that ſowed good Seed in his Field, <hi>Mat.</hi> 13. 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="61" facs="tcp:42947:31"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Enemy's Work at that day?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To ſow Tares among the good Seed, <hi>verſ.</hi> 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who ſowed the good Seed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Son of Man, <hi>verſ.</hi> 37.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Field in which it was ſown?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The World; and the good Seed were the Children of the King<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dom, <hi>verſ.</hi> 38.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Tares?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Children of the Wicked One, <hi>verſ.</hi> 38.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How many did Chriſt feed with five Loaves and two Fiſhes?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Five Thouſand Men beſides Women and Children, <hi>Matth.</hi> 14. 19, 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What remained after the Multitude was ſufficed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Twelve Baskets full, <hi>verſ.</hi> 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How many did Chriſt feed with ſeven Loves?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="62" facs="tcp:42947:32"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Seven Thouſand beſides Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men and Children, <hi>Mat.</hi> 15. 38.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why did the</hi> Scribes <hi>and</hi> Phariſees <hi>require a Sign from Heaven?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe they were a Wicked and an Adulterous Generation, <hi>Matth</hi> 16. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did Chriſt give them a Sign?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, ſave the Sign of the Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phet <hi>Jonah, Jonah</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did the Parable of the Vine<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>yard ſignifie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Unworthyneſs of the <hi>Jews,</hi> unto whom many Prophets and Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vants of God had been ſent, whom they had beaten and killed; and al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſo, how they would kill the Son of the Heir alſo, <hi>Matth.</hi> 21. 33, 34, 35, 36, 37, 38.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did the Parable of the Marriage of the King's Son ſignifie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The many Invitations which the Jews had, to come to the Mar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riage of the Lamb, and to the Table
<pb n="63" facs="tcp:42947:32"/>
of the Lord, which they regarded not, <hi>Mat.</hi> 22. 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the King's Sentence againſt thoſe who ſleighted his Invitations?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To ſend forth Warriors to de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroy them, and to invite Gueſs out of the Hedges and High-Wayes, that the Wedding might be furniſhed, <hi>verſ.</hi> 9, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Were they all worthy that came to the Marriage Dinner?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, there came one who had not the Wedding-Garment, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the King's Sentence againſt him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To bind him Hand and Foot, and caſt him into utter Darkneſs, there ſhall be Weeping and Gnaſhing of Teeth, <hi>verſ.</hi> 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Parable of the Ten Virgins?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>to ſhew unto the <hi>Scribes</hi> and <hi>Phariſees</hi> the Folly of their Out-ſide
<pb n="64" facs="tcp:42947:33"/>
Worſhip, and the neceſſity of the Life within, <hi>Mat.</hi> 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was ſignified by the Tallents?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To demonſtrate the difference between the Profitable and Unprofi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>table Servants, and that both had a Tallent given to profit withal, <hi>verſ.</hi> 15. <hi>to verſ.</hi> 30.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who conſulted together to kill Jeſus?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Chief Prieſts, and Scribes, and Elders of the People, <hi>Mat.</hi> 26. 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom was he delivered into their hands?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Judas Iſcariot,</hi> one of the twelve Diſciples, <hi>verſ.</hi> 48, 57.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>For what did</hi> Judas Iſcariot <hi>deliver him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For thirty Pieces of Silver, <hi>verſ.</hi> 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who delivered Christ bound to</hi> Pon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tius Pilate?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Chief Prieſts and Elders, <hi>Mat.</hi> 27. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="65" facs="tcp:42947:33"/>
               <speaker>S</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of</hi> Judas <hi>who betrayed Chriſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He Hanged himſelf, <hi>verſ.</hi> 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why would</hi> Pilate <hi>have releaſed Jeſus?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe he knew that for Envy the <hi>Jews</hi> had delivered Jeſus to him to be Crucified, <hi>Mat.</hi> 27. 17, 18.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who did the</hi> Jews <hi>deſire to be relea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed, and who to be crucified?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They cryed out, Let <hi>Barrabbas</hi> be Looſed, and let Jeſus be Crucifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed, <hi>Mat.</hi> 27. 21, 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did they looſe</hi> Barrabbas, <hi>and cru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cifie Jeſus?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, <hi>verſ.</hi> 26, 35.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who did they crucifie with him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Two Thieves, one on his Right Hand, and the other on his left, <hi>verſ.</hi> 38.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who took his Body from the Croſs?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Joſeph;</hi> and wrapped it in a Linnen Cloath, and put it in a new
<pb n="66" facs="tcp:42947:34"/>
Sepulchre which he had hew'd out of a Rock, <hi>Mat.</hi> 27. 59, 60.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>When did God raiſe Chriſt from the dead?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Within three dayes, as Chriſt had foretold, <hi>Mat.</hi> 28. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who ſhew'd unto</hi> Mary Magdalen, <hi>&amp; the other</hi> Mary <hi>the Reſurrection of Jeſus?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>An Angel from Heaven, <hi>v.</hi> 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Unto whem did he firſt appear after his Reſurrection?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto <hi>Mary Magdalen</hi> and the o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther <hi>Mary,</hi> as they were going to tell his Diſciples of his Reſurrection, and afterwards to his Diſciples in <hi>Galilee, verſ.</hi> 9, 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was Chriſt's Work in</hi> Galilee?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To preach the Goſpel through<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>out all their <hi>Synagogues,</hi> Mark 1. 39.</p>
               <p>2ly To heal the Palſie and caſt out the Unclean Spirit, <hi>Mark</hi> 1. 26. <hi>and</hi> 2. 4, 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did Chriſt declare to the People by the Sower of Seed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="76" facs="tcp:42947:34"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The ſtate of the Kingdom of God, <hi>Mark</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How many Sorts of Ground was the ſeed of the Kingdom Sown in?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Four Sorts; The High-Way Ground, the Stony Ground, the Thor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Ground, and the Good Ground, <hi>Mark</hi> 4. 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How many of them brought forth Fruit to Perfection?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>None but the Good Ground, <hi>Mark</hi> 4. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why did not the other three bring forth Fruit?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe the firſt retained not the ſeed at all, but the Fowls of the Air devoured it; and the ſecond but a little while, in which it having no depth of Earth withered a way; the third being Thorny, the ſeed was Choaked, ſo that it yelded no Fruit, <hi>Mark</hi> 4. 4, 5, 6, 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was the Kingdom of God like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned to a Grain of Muſterd ſeed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="68" facs="tcp:42947:35"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To ſhew the Smalneſs of the Seed of the Kingdom when it is firſt ſown, and how great it is when grown up, <hi>Mark</hi> 4. 31, 32.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who Beheaded</hi> John Baptiſt?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Herod, <hi>Mark</hi> 6. 27.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was the cauſe thereof?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Herodias,</hi> his Brothers <hi>Philip's</hi> Wife, <hi>verſ.</hi> 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why did the</hi> Phariſees <hi>Condemn the diſciples of Jeſus for Eating with Un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>waſhed Hands?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe they preferred the Tra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ditions of the Elders before the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandments of God, <hi>Mark</hi> 7. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did Chriſt ſay did Defile the Man?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Not to eat with Unwaſhed Hands; nor that which entereth in at the Mouth, but that which came out of the Mouth from the heart, as vain Thoughts, Murders, &amp;c. <hi>Mark</hi> 7. 18, &amp; 20. 21, 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Where was Chriſt Transfigured be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore his Diſciples?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="69" facs="tcp:42947:35"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In an High Mountain apart, <hi>Mark</hi> 9. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did Chriſt demonſtrate to his Diſciples by the Vineyard?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Juſtice of God againſt the <hi>Jews,</hi> who had beaten his Servants, and ſlain his Son, <hi>Mark</hi> 12. 2, 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Portion of theſe Huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band men?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To be deſtroyed, and the <hi>Vineyard</hi> to be taken from them, and given to others, <hi>Mark</hi> 12. 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who wrote the Third Book of the New Teſtament in the Bible?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Luke</hi> the Evangeliſt.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Subſtance of that Book.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A Rechearſal of what <hi>Matthew</hi> and <hi>Mark</hi> before had written of the Birth, Death, Sufferings, Temptati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and Works of Chriſt.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who wrote the Fourth Book of the New Teſtament?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>John</hi> the Evangeliſt.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his firſt Teſtimony of Chriſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="70" facs="tcp:42947:36"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of his Divinity; for his name was called the Word of God, by which all things were made, which Word be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>came Fleſh, <hi>Joh.</hi> 1, 1, 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his further Teſtimony of him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That he was the true Light, who lighted every man that came into the World, <hi>verſ.</hi> 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> John <hi>Baptiſt's Office and Commiſſion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To Baptize with water, <hi>John</hi> 1. 31.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was Chriſt</hi>'s <hi>Office or Work?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To Baptize with the holy Ghoſt and with fire, <hi>verſ.</hi> 33.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the firſt Miracle that Jeſus did in</hi> Cana <hi>of Galilee after his Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſurrection?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Turning of Water into Wine at the Marriage, <hi>John</hi> 2. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the New Birth which Chriſt Spoke of to</hi> Nicodemus?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Birth of the Spirit, which
<pb n="71" facs="tcp:42947:36"/>
he could not underſtand, <hi>John</hi> 3. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> John <hi>ſay was the Condem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nation of the World?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That Light was come into the World, and men loved Darkneſs ra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther then Light, becauſe their Deeds were Evil, <hi>John</hi> 3. 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Where did the woman of</hi> Samaria <hi>meet with Chriſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>At <hi>Jacob</hi>'s Well at <hi>Sychar</hi> a City of <hi>Samaria,</hi> John 4. 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did He teſtifie to the Woman of</hi> Samaria?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That the True Worſhippers ſhould worſhip the Father in Spirit and Truth, <hi>Joh.</hi> 4. 23, 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Wherefore did the</hi> Jews <hi>ſeek Occa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion to ſlay Chriſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe He healed a Man that was Sick eight and thirty years on the Sabbath-Day, <hi>John</hi> 5. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did Chriſt call himſelf?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Bread of Life, <hi>John</hi> 6. 35.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whom did Chriſt ſay, came unto him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="72" facs="tcp:42947:37"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Thoſe who had Heard and Lear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned of the Father, and whom the Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther drew, <hi>John</hi> 6. 44, 45.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whom did Chriſt ſay, could Eat his Fleſh, and Drink his Blood?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Thoſe who dwelt in him, and They, in whom <hi>He</hi> dwelt, <hi>verſ.</hi> 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Living Bread of which Chriſt ſpoke?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>His Fleſh, which <hi>He</hi> would give for the Life of the World, <hi>verſ.</hi> 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Could his Diſciples receive theſe Words?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, for they judged it a Hard Saying, <hi>verſ.</hi> 60.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did Jeſus again teſtifie of Himſelf?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That <hi>He</hi> was the Light of the World, and He who followed Him ſhould not abide in Darkneſs, but ſhould have the Light of Life, <hi>John</hi> 8. <hi>verſ.</hi> 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did Chriſt ſay of the Scribes and Phariſees?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="73" facs="tcp:42947:37"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they were of their Father the <hi>Devil,</hi> and the Luſt of their Fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther they would do, <hi>Joh.</hi> 8. 44.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was Chriſt's further Teſtimony of Himſelf?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That <hi>He</hi> was the Good Shep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>herd, <hi>John</hi> 10. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his Teſtimony of a Hireling?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That the Hireling, whoſe the Sheep is not, ſeeth the Wolf coming fleeth, and leaves the Sheep, <hi>verſ.</hi> 12, 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What doth the Good Shepherd for his Sheep?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He knoweth his Sheep, and is known of them, and layeth down his Life for his Sheep, <hi>verſ.</hi> 14, 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How is the Sheep of Chriſt known?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They hear his Voyce and follow him, and <hi>He</hi> giveth unto them Eter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nal Life, <hi>Joh.</hi> 10. 27, 28.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What other Miracle did Chriſt in the Sight of the Jews?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He raiſed <hi>Lazarus</hi> from the Dead
<pb n="74" facs="tcp:42947:38"/>
who had been dead four dayes, <hi>Joh.</hi> 11. 39, 43, 44.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who firſt conſpired the Death of Chriſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Caiphas</hi> the High-Prieſt, he with the Phariſees ſaying, <hi>If we let him alone all People will believe on him, and the</hi> Romans <hi>would come, and take their City and Nation, John</hi> 11. 48.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was ſignified by the Parable of the Wheat-Corn?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That thoſe who would live with Chriſt, and bring forth Fruit, ſhould dye with Him, <hi>John</hi> 12. 24, 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Unto what did Chriſt exhort his Diſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples and Followers?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To walk in the Light while they had the Light, leaſt Darkneſs came upon them, <hi>verſ.</hi> 35, 36.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>For what End came Chriſt into the World?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That whoſoever believed in him ſhould not abide in Darkneſs, <hi>verſ.</hi> 46.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who were they whom Chriſt ſaid Lo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved Him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="75" facs="tcp:42947:38"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They who had his Command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, and kept them, <hi>John</hi> 13. 21.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why did Chriſt go away in the Fleſh out of the World?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That <hi>He</hi> might come again in the Spirit, <hi>Joh.</hi> 14. 28.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Comforter which Chriſt promiſed to ſend his Diſciples after his De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>parture, which ſhould teach them all things?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Spirit of Truth which the World could not receive, <hi>John</hi> 14. 17. &amp; 16. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whom did Chriſt call his Friends?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Thoſe who did his Command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments, <hi>John</hi> 15. 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Office of the Comforter whom Chriſt would ſend?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To reprove the World of Sin, of Righteouſneſs and Judgment.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why of Sin?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe they believe not on him, <hi>verſ.</hi> 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why of Righteouſneſs?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe <hi>He</hi> went to the Father,
<pb n="76" facs="tcp:42947:39"/>
and they ſaw Him no more, <hi>verſ.</hi> 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why of Judgment?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe the Prince of this World was judged, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was the Diſciples of Chriſt ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted of the World?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe they were not of the World, even as He was not of the World, <hi>John</hi> 17. 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Acts of the Apoſtles?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Luke</hi> the Evangeliſt, <hi>Act.</hi> 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the Subſtance of that Book?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Wonderfull Work of the Lord in pouring out of his Spirit upon his Sons and Daughters, according to his Promiſe by <hi>Joel</hi> 2. 28. <hi>Act.</hi> 1. 2 <hi>Chap.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did the Holy Ghoſt manifeſt it<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelf to the Apoſtles as they waited at</hi> Jeru<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>As the Ruſhing of a mighty Wind from Heaven, and it filled the Houſe where they ſate, <hi>Act.</hi> 2. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What Miracles did the Apoſtles after</hi>
                  <pb n="77" facs="tcp:42947:39"/>
                  <hi>they had received the Holy Ghoſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Firſt, Three Thouſand was ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded to the Church by <hi>Peter</hi>'s Sermon, <hi>Acts</hi> 2. 41.</p>
               <p>2. The Raiſing of the Criple who ſat at the Gate of the Temple, <hi>Acts</hi> 3. 6, 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Wherefore was</hi> Ananias <hi>and</hi> Saphi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ra <hi>deſtroyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For Lying againſt the Holy Ghoſt, <hi>Acts</hi> 5. 5, 6, 7, 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God manifeſt his Power unto the Apoſtle in Priſon?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In bringing them out when the Doors were ſhut, and Keepers watch<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>Acts</hi> 5. 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> Stephen<hi>'s Teſtimony for God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That He dwelt not in Temples made with hands, <hi>Acts</hi> 7. 48.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Wherefore did they Stone</hi> Stephen <hi>to Death?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>For Teſtifying unto <hi>Jeſus</hi> the Reſurrection, <hi>Acts</hi> 7. 57, 58.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="78" facs="tcp:42947:40"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom was</hi> Samaria <hi>Seduced</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Simon Magus, Acts</hi> 8. 9, 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came</hi> Simon Magus <hi>to believe the Goſpel?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Preaching of <hi>Philip,</hi> and the Power, and Authority that God manifeſted with him, <hi>Acts</hi> 8. <hi>verſ.</hi> 12, 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom was the Eunuch (the Queen of the Aethiopians chief Governour) Converted and Baptized?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Philip, Acts</hi> 8. 35, 36, 37, 38.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was the greateſt Perſecutour of the Church of Chriſt among the</hi> Jews?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Saul, Acts</hi> 8. 3, &amp; 9, 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came he to be ſtop't from Perſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, and to beleeve the Goſpel?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He was ſtruck down by a Light from Heaven, and a Voyce from God ſaying <hi>Saul, Saul</hi> why perſecuteſt thou me, <hi>Acts</hi> 9. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither was he going when the Lord Smote him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To <hi>Damaſcus</hi> with Letters from
<pb n="79" facs="tcp:42947:40"/>
the high Prieſts to perſecute the Diſci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ples of Chriſt, whether men or women, and to bring them bound to <hi>Jeruſalem, Acts</hi> 9. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By whom did</hi> Paul <hi>Receive his Sight?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By <hi>Ananias,</hi> who put his Hands upon him, and his Eyes were opened, and he Received the Holy Ghoſt, and ſtraight-way preached Chriſt in <hi>Da<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>maſcus, Acts</hi> 9. 17, 18, 12, 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did</hi> Saul <hi>continue with the Diſciples ſtedfast in Faith and Doctrine?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, and preached Chriſt bold<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly in the Synagogues, and confounded the <hi>Jews,</hi> both at <hi>Damaſcus,</hi> and at <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> inſomuch that the <hi>Jews</hi> took Counſel together to Kill him, <hi>Acts</hi> 9. 21, 22, 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was he delivered out of their Hands?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Diſciples who put him through the wall, and let him down in a Basket, <hi>Acts</hi> 9. 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="80" facs="tcp:42947:41"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was ſignified by</hi> Peter's <hi>Viſion of the veſſel let down from Heaven, in which was all manner of four-footed Beaſts, Fowles of the Air, and Creeping Things?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That God would not Reſpect the Perſon of the <hi>Jew,</hi> nor <hi>Gentile,</hi> but of every Nation, they who feared him, and wrought Righteouſneſs was Accepted of him, <hi>Acts</hi> 10. 34, 35.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who was next Perſecutour of the Chriſtians?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Herod</hi> who Killed <hi>James</hi> the Brother of <hi>John</hi> with the Sword, and took <hi>Peter</hi> and put him in Priſon, <hi>Acts</hi> 12. 1, 2, 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God manifeſt his Diſplea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure againſt him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He ſent his Angel who ſmote him, and he was eaten of Worms, <hi>Acts</hi> 12. 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whom did God ordain to be</hi> Paul's <hi>Companion to Preach the Goſpel?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Barnabas, <hi>Acts</hi> 13. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who firſt withſtood their Doctrine?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="81" facs="tcp:42947:41"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Elymas</hi> the Sorcerer, <hi>Acts</hi> 13. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God manifeſt his wrath againſt him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In ſmiting him with Blind<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, ſo that he went about ſeek<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing ſome to lead him by the hand, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did the</hi> Jews <hi>Receive the Teſti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mony of</hi> Paul <hi>and</hi> Barnabas?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, for they were full of Envy, and ſpake againſt them, and railed on them, ſo that they turned to the Gen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tiles, <hi>verſ.</hi> 45, 46.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did the</hi> Gentiles <hi>believe the Goſpel?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, with Gladneſs, and Glorified the Word of God, <hi>Acts</hi> 13. 47, 48.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither went</hi> Paul <hi>and</hi> Barnabas, <hi>after?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To <hi>Iconium</hi> and <hi>Lyſtra,</hi> where the <hi>Jews</hi> cauſed <hi>Paul</hi> to be ſtoned, and drew him out of the City for dead, <hi>Acts</hi> 14. 1, 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Was the Gentiles, who did believe, enjoyned to be Circumciſed after the Law of</hi> Moſes?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="82" facs="tcp:42947:42"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, they were only to abſtain from Filthineſs of Idols and fornica<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, from things ſtrangled, and from Blood.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who Circumciſed</hi> Timothy?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul</hi> becauſe of the <hi>Jews</hi> that was in thoſe Quarters knowing all that his Father was a Grecian, <hi>Acts</hi> 16. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was the Damſel healed who had the Spirit of Divinations?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Power and Spirit of God in <hi>Paul</hi> for which her Maſter caus'd <hi>Paul</hi> and <hi>Sylas</hi> to be ſore beaten and caſt into Priſon, <hi>Acts</hi> 16. 18, 21, 22, 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did God deliver them and looſe their hands?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By a mighty Power from Hea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven, which ſhook the Foundation of the Priſon, and opened all the Doors, and looſed every mans Bonds, <hi>verſ.</hi> 26.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did the Goaler feel the mighty Power of God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea, he and his whole houſe
<pb n="83" facs="tcp:42947:42"/>
was Converted and baptized, <hi>Act</hi> 16. 32, 33.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither did</hi> Paul <hi>paſs after he was ſet at Liberty?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To <hi>Theſſalonica,</hi> where he went into a ſynagogue of the <hi>Jews,</hi> and preached unto them Chriſt, <hi>Acts</hi> 17. 2, 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did the</hi> Jews <hi>Receive him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Some of them believed, and they who believed not made a Tu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mult in the City, and aſſaulted the houſe of <hi>Jaſon</hi> to bring <hi>Paul</hi> and <hi>Silas</hi> 
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ut to the People, <hi>verſ.</hi> 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did</hi> Paul <hi>and</hi> Silas <hi>eſcape their <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ands?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They were ſent away by night <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>o <hi>Berea,</hi> where the <hi>Bereans</hi> received <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>he word with all readineſs, and ſear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>hed the Scriptures daily whether <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>heſe things were ſo, <hi>Acts</hi> 17. 10, 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither did</hi> Paul <hi>paſs from</hi> Berea?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To <hi>Athens</hi> where he ſhewed the <hi>
                     <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>thenians</hi> their Idolatry, and that
<pb n="84" facs="tcp:42947:43"/>
God who made the World dwelt not in Temples made with hands, <hi>v.</hi> 24, 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither did</hi> Paul <hi>paſs from</hi> Athens?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To <hi>Corinthus,</hi> where he found <hi>Aquila</hi> and <hi>Pricilla,</hi> who was come out of <hi>Italy</hi> at the Command of <hi>Claudius, Acts</hi> 18. 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How long did</hi> Paul <hi>continue at</hi> Co<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rinthus?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A Year and ſix Moneths, teaching the Word of God, <hi>verſ.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What Miracles was done by him there?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The holy Ghoſt was given unto the Diſciples by the laying on of his Hands, <hi>Acts</hi> 19. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did not the Vagabond</hi> Jews, <hi>when they ſaw what miracles was done by the hand of</hi> Paul, <hi>take upon them to Caſt out the Unclean Spirits in the name of Jeſus?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Yea they did, but that Evil Spirit overcame them, and ran upon them, ſo that they fled out naked and wounded, <hi>Acts</hi> 13. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who raiſed</hi> Eutychus <hi>from the dead?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Paul, <hi>Acts</hi> 20. 10, 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="85" facs="tcp:42947:43"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who Propheſied of</hi> Paul's <hi>Bonds at</hi> Jeruſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Agabus,</hi> a Prophet of <hi>Judea, Act.</hi> 21. 10, 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Where was</hi> Paul <hi>taken at</hi> Jeruſalem?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the Temple, where the <hi>Jews</hi> moved the People againſt him, ſay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing he taught all men every where againſt the People, and the Law, and brought <hi>Grecians</hi> into the Temple polu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting that Holy Place, <hi>Acts</hi> 21. 27, 28.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did the People to</hi> Paul?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They took him and drew him out of the Temple and beat him, intend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing to kill him, <hi>verſ.</hi> 30. 31.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What hindred them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Tydings of an uproar in <hi>Jeruſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lem, verſ.</hi> 31, 32.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What became of</hi> Paul <hi>afterwards?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Chief Captain delivered him to be Scurged, <hi>Acts</hi> 22. 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How did he eſcape their hands?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By pleading that he was a <hi>Ro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man,</hi> and uncondemned, <hi>Acts</hi> 22. 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="86" facs="tcp:42947:44"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who accuſed</hi> Paul <hi>to the Gover<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nour?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Turtullus</hi> a certain Orator, and of the <hi>Jews</hi> alſo who could not prov<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> their Accuſations, <hi>Acts</hi> 24. 1, 9, 13<g ref="char:punc">▪</g>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Of what did</hi> Paul <hi>reaſon befor<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi> Felix?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of Righteouſneſs, Temperanc<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and Judgment to come which cauſe<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>Falix</hi> to Tremble, <hi>Acts</hi> 24. 26.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>For what end was</hi> Paul <hi>ſent to th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> Gentiles?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To open the eyes of the Blin<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> and to turn them from darkneſs t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Light, and from the Power of Sata<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> unto God, &amp;c. <hi>Acts</hi> 26. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who first writ to the Romans?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul, Rom.</hi> 1. Chap.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Goſpel he Preached t<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Power of God to Salvatio<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> to every one that believed <hi>Rom.</hi> 1. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was the wrath of God reveale<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> from Heaven againſt all ungodlineſs an<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> unrighteouſneſs of men?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="87" facs="tcp:42947:44"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe that which might be known of God was manifeſted in them &amp;c. <hi>Rom.</hi> 1. 18, 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Why was the Gentiles juſtified rather then the</hi> Jews?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Becauſe, the <hi>Jews</hi> believed not, but were only Hearers of the Law outwardly; but the Gentles believing, did the things Contained in the Law, having it written in their hearts <hi>Rom.</hi> 2. 13, 14, 15. <hi>Chap.</hi> 9. 30, 31.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Was any man juſtified by the works of the Law?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No, <hi>Rom.</hi> 3. 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How is man juſtified before God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Freely by the grace of God through the Redemption that is in Chriſt Jeſus, <hi>Rom.</hi> 3. 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How Long did ſin and death raign over all mankind?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>From <hi>Adam</hi> till <hi>Moſes,</hi> even over them that had not ſinned after the ſimilitude of <hi>Adams</hi> tranſgreſſion, <hi>Rom.</hi> 4. 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="88" facs="tcp:42947:45"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How came ſin and death to be de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtroyed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By the Reigning of Grace through righteouſnes to Eternal Life, <hi>Rom.</hi> 5. 21.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the Wages of ſin?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Death; but the gift of God is Eternal Life through Jeſus Chriſt our Lord, <hi>Rom</hi> 6. 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who are Sons and Heirs of God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Thoſe who are Led by the Spi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rit of God <hi>Rom,</hi> 8. 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what doth the Election of God ſtand?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In the promiſed Seed, which is Chriſt, <hi>Rom.</hi> 9. 8. <hi>Gal.</hi> 3. 16. <hi>Epheſ.</hi> 1. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what was</hi> Jſraels <hi>Blindneſs and Ig<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>norance?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In that they had a Zeal for God, but not according to knowledge, being Ignorant of Gods righteouſneſs, and going about to Eſtabliſh their own, <hi>Rom.</hi> 10. 2, 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what did the Righteouſneſs of Faith conſiſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In Hearing, Believing, and O<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>beying
<pb n="89" facs="tcp:42947:45"/>
the Word of Faith, which was nigh, in the Heart, and in the Mouth, <hi>Rom.</hi> 10. 6, 7, 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>By what did the</hi> Gentiles <hi>ſtand upon the Root, when the</hi> Jews <hi>were broken off?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>By Faith, <hi>Rom.</hi> 11. 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Paul <hi>exhort the</hi> Romans <hi>unto in the Twelfth Chapter?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Not to Faſhion themſelves ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to the Courſe of this World <hi>&amp;c. Rom.</hi> 12. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did He further excite them unto in the Thirteenth Chapter?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To be Subject to the Higher Powers, which were a Terror to Evil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>doers, and a Praiſe to them who did Well, <hi>Rom.</hi> 13. 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did He further enjoyn them unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they might not Judge one another in Meats or Drinks, or in re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpect of an Holy Day, <hi>Rom</hi> 14. 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How were they to Eat, and keep a Day to the Lord?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They were to Eat in Faith; for he
<pb n="90" facs="tcp:42947:46"/>
that Doubted was Condemned if he Eat, and whatſoever was not of Faith was Sin, <hi>Rom.</hi> 14. 23.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Concluſion of</hi> Paul<hi>'s Epiſtle to the</hi> Romans?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To exhort them to Love one an<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>other by the Example of Chriſt, and to beware of Falſe Brethren, who through good Words, and Fair Spee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ches deceive the Hearts of the Simple, <hi>Rom.</hi> 16. 17, 18.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the firſt Epiſtle to the Corin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thians?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul,</hi> who exhorted them to be of one Mind, and to ſpeak one thing; and to avoid Contentions, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 1. 10, 11, 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>For what End was the Preaching of</hi> Paul <hi>amongſt the</hi> Corinthians?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That their Faith might not ſtand in the Wiſdom of Words, but in the Power of God, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 2. 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Was any able to know the things of God without the Spirit of God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="91" facs="tcp:42947:46"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No for as no man knew the things of a man, ſave the Spirit of man that was in him, ſo the things of God knew no man, but by the Spirit of God, 1 <hi>Cor</hi> 2. 11, 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what did the Kingdom of God ſtand?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Not in Words, but in Power, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 4. 2<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Paul <hi>Exhort Husbands and Wives unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To dwell with each other ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to knowledge and not to depart one from another, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 7. <hi>Chap.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he ſay of Circumciſion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He ſaid that neither Circumci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion nor Uncircumciſion availed any thing, but the keeping of the Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandments of God, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 7. 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he ſay to Believers Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cerning Meats?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That whatſoever was ſold on the ſhambles they, might Eat asking no queſtion for Conſcience ſake, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 10. 25.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="92" facs="tcp:42947:47"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Cup of Bleſſing which the Apoſtles Bleſſed?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Communion of the Blood of Chriſt, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 10. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Bread which they Brake?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Communion of the Body of Chriſt, <hi>verſ.</hi> 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Paul <hi>ſay Concerning the Reſurrection of the Body?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That God giveth a Body as it pleaſeth him, and to every Seed his own Body, 1 <hi>Cor.</hi> 15. 37, 38.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Where was the Light which gave the Apoſtles the Knowledge of the Glory of God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In their Hearts, which Treaſure they had in Earthen Veſſels, 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 4. 6, 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>In what was the Death and Life of Chriſt manifeſted amongſt the Apoſtles?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In their Mortal Fleſh, 2 <hi>Cor.</hi> 4. <hi>verſ.</hi> 11.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who wrote the Epiſtle to the</hi> Gala<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tians?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="93" facs="tcp:42947:47"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul,</hi> who reproved them for tur<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning to another Goſpel, <hi>Gal.</hi> 1. 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did He teſtifie among them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The End of the Law, and where fore it was added; and the Obedi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ence of Faith, through which they were Sons, and Heirs of God, <hi>Gal.</hi> 3, 4. Chap.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>2ly,</hi> The Bondage of the Law, and the Freedom in Chriſt, <hi>Gal.</hi> 5. 1, 2, 3.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>3ly,</hi> The Fruits of the Fleſh, and the Fruits of the Spirit, <hi>Gal.</hi> 5. 19.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>4ly,</hi> That thoſe that were Chriſt's, had crucified the Fleſh, with the Affe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctions and Luſts, <hi>Gal.</hi> 5. 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Epiſtle to the</hi> Ephe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſians?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul, Epheſ.</hi> 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the Subſtance of that Epiſtle?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To ſet forth unto them, being <hi>Gentiles,</hi> the Glory of Chriſt, and the Unity of the Spirit of Grace, through which they were Sanctified, and to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hort them unto Love and Meekneſs, <hi>Chap.</hi> 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="94" facs="tcp:42947:48"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did He Teſtifie of the Light?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That all things that are repro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved are made manifeſt by the Light, and that which maketh all things ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſt is Light, <hi>Epheſ.</hi> 5. 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Paul <hi>Exhort Children<g ref="char:punc">▪</g> unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To Obey their Parents, and to Honour their Father &amp; Mother, which is the firſt Commandment with Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſe, <hi>Epheſ.</hi> 6. 1, 2, 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he exhort Parents unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Not to provoke their Children to Wrath, but to bring them up in the Ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>monition of the Lord, <hi>Eph.</hi> 6. 4</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Fpiſtle to the</hi> Philip<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pians?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul, Phil.</hi> 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did He exhort the</hi> Philippians <hi>unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To Humility by the Example of Chriſt, <hi>Phil.</hi> 2. 3, 4, 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did He Teſtifie of Circumciſion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they were the Circumciſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on
<pb n="95" facs="tcp:42947:48"/>
who worſhipped God in the Spirit, <hi>Phil.</hi> 3. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Epiſtle to the</hi> Coloſſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ans?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul,</hi> who earneſtly prayed for an Increaſe of their Faith and Know<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, <hi>Col.</hi> 1. 9.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who wrote the Epiſtle to the</hi> Theſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſalonians?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul,</hi> who thanked God for their Stedfaſtneſs in Faith and good Works, 1 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 1. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did He Teſtifie of them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they were Children of the Light, and of the Day, therefore ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>horted them to Watch, and be So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ber, 1 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 5. 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Second Epiſtle to the</hi> Theſſalonians?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul,</hi> who teſtified that their Church was in God the Father, and in the Lord Jeſus Chriſt, 2 <hi>Theſſ.</hi> 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Epiſtle to</hi> Timothy?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul,</hi> who Exhorted <hi>Timothy</hi> to
<pb n="96" facs="tcp:42947:49"/>
wait upon his office, and to ſee that nothing but the Doctrine of Chriſt was preached, 1 <hi>Tim.</hi> 1. 3.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>2ly,</hi> He Exhorteth Women to ara<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> themſelves in modeſt Aparrel, and no<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> with Brodered Hair, or Gold, or Pearls, &amp;c, 1 <hi>Tim.</hi> 2. 9.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>3ly,</hi> In the 2d Epiſtle he tells him of Perrilous Times, and of the Marks and Fruits of the falſe Prophets; and deſires him to turn away from ſuch who had the Form, but not the Power of Godli<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſs, 2 <hi>Tim.</hi> 3. <hi>Chap.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Epiſtle to</hi> Titus?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul, Titus</hi> 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the Subſtance of that Epiſtle?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To ſtir him up to Execute the office of a Biſhop or Overſeer, with all Gravity and Integrity, <hi>Tit.</hi> 2. 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who writ the Epiſtle to</hi> Philemon?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Paul,</hi> who with many Sound Ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>guments exhorted <hi>Philemon</hi> to Receive <hi>Oneſimus</hi> again and to forgive the In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jury done him.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="97" facs="tcp:42947:49"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What is the Subſtance of the Book of the</hi> Hebrews.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To Set forth the difference of the firſt and ſecond Prieſthood, and of the Glory, Power and Excellency of the Miniſtry of Chriſt, <hi>Heb.</hi> 1. to the 8. <hi>Chap.</hi>
               </p>
               <p>
                  <hi>2ly,</hi> The ending of the Ceremonies of the Law, and the reaſon of the abo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liſhing thereof, becauſe it could not make perfect the comers thereunto, as pertaining to the Conſcience, <hi>Chap.</hi> 9. 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was Faith ſaid to be, to the Hebrews?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Evidence of things, not ſeen, and the Subſtance of things, hoped for, <hi>Heb.</hi> 11. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Effects and Fruits of Faith to our fore-Fathers?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Great victories over their Enemies and a good report, though they received not the promiſe, <hi>Heb.</hi> 11. whole Chap.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="98" facs="tcp:42947:50"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> James <hi>call pure Religion?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To viſit the Fatherleſs and Widdows, and to keep himſelf unſpot<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted of the World, <hi>James</hi> 1. 27.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> James <hi>forbid in the Se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond Chapter?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That his Brethren ſhould not have the Faith of Jeſus with reſpect of Perſons, <hi>Jam.</hi> 2. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the dead Faith which</hi> James <hi>Spake of, and what was the Living Faith?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That dead Faith was without works, and the Living Faith wrought by Love, <hi>James</hi> 2. 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> James <hi>Exhort his Bre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thren unto in the 5th Chapter?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That above all things, they ſhould not Swear at all, <hi>James</hi> 5. 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Unto whom did</hi> Peter <hi>write?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto the Strangers who dwelt through <hi>Pontus, Galatia, Capadocia, Aſia</hi> and <hi>Bythinia,</hi> 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he Exhort them unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To gird up the Loins of their
<pb n="99" facs="tcp:42947:50"/>
Minds, and be Sober, truſting Perfectly on the Grace of God, that as he, who had called them is holy, that they ſhould be Holy in all manner of Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſation, 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 1. 13, 14, 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he Exhort Women to?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That their adorning ſhould not be outward, as with Broidered Hair, Gold, or Pearl, &amp;c. 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 3. 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How were they to be adorned?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>With a quiet and meek Spirit, after the manner of the Holy Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men of God, 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 3, 4, 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Saving Baptiſm which</hi> Peter <hi>ſpake of?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Not the putting away of the Filth of the Fleſh, but the anſwer of a good Conſcience, by the Reſurrecti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on of <hi>Jeſus,</hi> 1 <hi>Pet.</hi> 3. 20, 21.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he Exhort Paſtors unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To Feed the Flock of Chriſt, not by Conſtraint, but willingly; not for filthy Lucre, but of a ready mind, 1 <hi>Peter</hi> 5. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="100" facs="tcp:42947:51"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he further Exhort the Saints unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To be ſober, and watch; for the Enemy, as a Roaring Lyon, walketh about ſeeking whom he may devour, 1 <hi>Peter</hi> 5. 8.</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>2ly,</hi> To make their Calling and Election ſure?</p>
               <p>
                  <hi>3ly,</hi> That they had a more ſure word of Propheſie, then that voice which was heard in the Mount, unto which he Exhorted them to take heed unto, untill the day dawned, and the Day-Star aroſe in their hearts, 2 <hi>Pet.</hi> 1. 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was this more ſure word of Propheſie?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Light wherewith Chriſt had enlightened them, <hi>verſ.</hi> 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he warn the Saints of?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Of falſe Prophets, who through Covetouſneſs, with feigned words, would make merchandize of them, 2 <hi>Pet</hi> 2. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What further Marks had the falſe Prophets?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="101" facs="tcp:42947:51"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They had Eyes full of Adultery, that could not ceaſe from ſin, and Hearts exerciſed with Covetous Pra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ctices, &amp;c. 2 <hi>Pet.</hi> 2. 14.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was</hi> John<hi>'s Teſtimony of God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M,</speaker>
               <p>That he was Light, and in him was no Darkneſs at all; and if they walked in rhe Light, as he was in the Light, they had Fellowſhip one with another, and the Blood of Chriſt clean<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed them from all Sin, 1 <hi>John</hi> 1. 6, 7.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was the Love of God perfected in them?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In keeping of the Command<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ments of God, 1 <hi>John</hi> 2. 5.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>How was the Lying ſpirit manifeſted?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>In pretending Love to God, and Knowledge of Him, and yet kept not his Commandments, <hi>verſ.</hi> 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> John <hi>tell the little Chil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dren?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That it was the Laſt Time, and that they had heard that Antichriſt
<pb n="102" facs="tcp:42947:52"/>
ſhould come, and that even already there were many Antichriſts, <hi>verſ.</hi> 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Where had they heard that Antichriſt ſhould come?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Chriſt had fore-told it, <hi>Mat.</hi> 7. &amp; 24. <hi>cap.</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was his further Exhortations?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That no man might deceive them; for none was Righteous, but him that did Righteouſneſs; for he that com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted Sin was of the Devil: and a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gain, whoſoever ſinneth, hath not ſeen him, neither known him, 1 <hi>John</hi> 3. 6, 7, 8.</p>
               <p>2ly. In this was the Children of God manifeſted, and the Children of the Devil, <hi>verſ.</hi> 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did John ſay of them that did believe?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That they had the Witneſs in themſelves, 1 <hi>Joh.</hi> 3. 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did</hi> Jude <hi>exhort the Saints unto?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="103" facs="tcp:42947:52"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Earneſtly to contend for the Faith delivered them, <hi>Jude</hi> 1. 3.</p>
               <p>2ly, To beware of Falſe Prophets, who walk'd after their own Luſts, <hi>v.</hi> 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who wrote the</hi> Revelation?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>John</hi> the Divine, <hi>Rev.</hi> 1. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Unto whom did he write?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Unto the Seven Churches of <hi>Aſia,</hi> verſ. 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whom did he ſee as Head and Chief of the Seven Churches?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Chriſt the Son of God deſcen<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded from Heaven, <hi>ver,</hi> 13.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Unto what did he exhort the Church of</hi> Epheſus?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To Repent, and do her firſt Work, having (after much Suffering) for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaken her firſt Love, <hi>Rev.</hi> 2. 4, 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he write to the Church at</hi> Smyrna?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Not to fear thoſe things that ſhould come upon them; telling them, the Devil ſhould caſt ſome of them into Priſon, and they ſhould be
<pb n="104" facs="tcp:42947:53"/>
Perſecuted Ten Dayes: but be tho<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Faithful unto Death, and I will giv<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> thee a Crown of Life, <hi>ver.</hi> 10.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did Chriſt promiſe to him tha<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap> overcame?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To give him of the hidden Man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>na, and a White Stone, and in it a New Name written, which none knew but he that had it, <hi>ver.</hi> 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he further Promiſe to him that overcame?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>That he ſhould be clothed in White, and his Name ſhould not be blotted out of the Book of Life, <hi>Rev.</hi> 3. 5.</p>
               <p>
                  <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>ly, That he would make him a Pillar in the Temple of God, and he ſhall go no more out; and he would write upon him the Name of God, and the Name of the City of my God, <hi>v.</hi> 12.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did he write to the Church of</hi> Laodicea?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That ſhe was neither Hot nor Cold, and therefore the Lord would
<pb n="105" facs="tcp:42947:53"/>
ſpue her out of his Mouth, <hi>ver.</hi> 15, 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Token of Chriſt's Love to his People?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>That he Rebukes and Chaſtens them, <hi>verſ.</hi> 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What did Chriſt further promiſe to him that Overcometh?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>He would grant him to ſit with him in his Throne, even as he over-came, and ſate with his Father in his Throne, <hi>verſ.</hi> 21.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who ſate on the Throne (that was ſet in Heaven) at the Right-hand of the Ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jeſty of God?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Lamb, <hi>Rev.</hi> 4. 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Sealed Book which none in Heaven nor Earth was worthy to open, but the Lyon of the Tribe of</hi> Judah?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Book of God's Judgments and Righteouſneſs, <hi>Rev.</hi> 5, 6, cap.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Woman that appeared in Heaven clothed with the Sun?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The true Spouſe, the Lamb's Wife, or True Church, <hi>Rev.</hi> 12. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="106" facs="tcp:42947:54"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who appeared againſt her, to deſtroy the Man-Child, with whom ſhe travelled?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A Great Red Dragon, <hi>verſ.</hi> 3.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither did the Woman flee to ſave her ſelf?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Into the Wilderneſs, where ſhe had a Place prepared of God, <hi>verſ.</hi> 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who were they who worſhipped the Beaſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>They whoſe Names were not written in the Lamb's Book of Life, <hi>Rev.</hi> 13. 8.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Who ſtood with the Lamb upon Mount</hi> Zion?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>An Hundred Forty and Four Thouſand, having their Father's Name written in their Fore-Heads, <hi>Rev.</hi> 14. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was purpoſed by the Harveſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The cutting down of the Vines of the Earth, and the caſting of them into the Wine-Preſs of the Wrath of God, <hi>verſ.</hi> 19.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was ſignified by the Woman ar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rayed</hi>
                  <pb n="107" facs="tcp:42947:54"/>
                  <hi>in Purple and Scarlet, and gilded with Gold, who had a Golden Cup in her hand full of Abomination?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Falſe Church, or Myſtery <hi>Babylon,</hi> the Mother of Whoredoms, who was drunk with the Blood of the Saints and Martyrs of Jeſus, <hi>Rev.</hi> 17. 4, 5, 6.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Waters on which the Whore ſate?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They are Peoples, and Multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tudes, and Nations, and Tongues, <hi>v.</hi> 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Ten Horns?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Thoſe that ſhould hate the Whore and make her deſolate, and burn her Fleſh with Fire, <hi>verſ.</hi> 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was God's Decree concerning the Whore of</hi> Babylon?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Her total Overthrow and De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtruction, with all her Merchants and Lovers, <hi>Rev.</hi> 18. cap.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was rendered unto God for his <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>uſtice upon the Great Whore?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="180" facs="tcp:42947:55"/>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Praiſes and Hallelujah from his Saints in Heaven. <hi>Rev.</hi> 19. 1, 2.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Lamb's Name who ſate upon the White Horſe?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Word of God, <hi>verſ.</hi> 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Portion of the Beaſt and the Falſe Prophet, which had wrought Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>racles before him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They both were caſt alive into the Lake of Fire, burning with Brim<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtone, <hi>verſ.</hi> 20.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Whither was the Dragon the Old Ser<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pent caſt?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Into the <hi>bottomleſs Pit,</hi> in which he was ſhut, and the Door ſeal'd upon him, that he might deceive the People no more, till a thouſand years was expir'd, <hi>Rev.</hi> 20. 3, 4.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>To what was the Heavenly</hi> Jeruſalem <hi>likened?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>To a Bride adorned for her Huſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>band.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>What was the Compaſs of the Heavenly</hi>
                  <pb n="109" facs="tcp:42947:55"/>
Jeruſalem, <hi>whoſe Length, Breadth and Heighth are equal?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Twelve thouſand Furlongs, <hi>Rev.</hi> 21. 16.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Did</hi> John <hi>ſee an outward Temple in the Heavenly City?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; for the Lord God and the Lamb was the Temple of it, <hi>verſ.</hi> 22.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>Had the City any need of the Sun, Moon or Candle?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>No; for the Glory of God did light it, and the Lamb was the Light thereof; and the People who were ſa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ved, walked in the Light thereof, <hi>verſ.</hi> 24.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>VVhat did the Angel further ſhew unto</hi> John?</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>A pure River of Water of Life, clear as Cryſtal, proceeding out of the Throne of God, <hi>Rev.</hi> 22. 1.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>VVhat more did he ſhew him?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Tree of Life, which bare twelve manner of Fruits, <hi>verſ.</hi> 2.</p>
               <pb n="180" facs="tcp:42947:56"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
               <pb n="109" facs="tcp:42947:56"/>
               <gap reason="duplicate" extent="1 page">
                  <desc>〈1 page duplicate〉</desc>
               </gap>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <pb n="110" facs="tcp:42947:57"/>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>VVho had Right to the Tree of Life and to enter into the City?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>They who did the Command<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>ments of the Lamb.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>VVho were ſhut out of the City?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>The Dogs, Whoremongers, and Murderers, and Idolaters, and whoſo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ever loveth and maketh Lyes, <hi>verſ.</hi> 15.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>VVho did the Lamb invite to come and Drink of the VVater of Life?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>Whoſoever was a Thirſt, <hi>verſ.</hi> 17.</p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>S.</speaker>
               <p>
                  <hi>VVhat was the Lot of him who added or diminiſhed to or from the Prophecy of the Book?</hi>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <sp>
               <speaker>M.</speaker>
               <p>God would add to him (who ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ded) all the Plagues written in th<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap> Book.</p>
               <p>And he that diminiſheth, God wou<gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap> take his Part out of the Book of Life, and out of the Holy City, <hi>verſ.</hi> 18, <gap reason="illegible" resp="#APEX" extent="2 letters">
                     <desc>••</desc>
                  </gap>
               </p>
            </sp>
            <closer>
               <signed>Ambroſe Rigge.</signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>THE END.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:42947:57"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
